[
    {
        "front": "which elements of sap fiori can be assigned to business roles?",
        "back": "Spaces, Business Catalog Groups, Business Catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "How can you activate an extension for the sap fiori launchpad(FLP)?",
        "back": "Target Mapping(/UI2/FLPD_CUST),Customer Settings(/UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF)"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the current UI technologies of SAP?",
        "back": "SAPUI5, Web Dynpro ABAP/Floorplan Manager, Dynpro"
    },
    {
        "front": "Why does it make sense to use navigation API of SAPUI5 and concepts such as eventbus or the navcontainer functions of the base application?",
        "back": "Using the navigation API, It is possible to use bookmarks; Using the navigation API, the configuration of routes and targets are clearly separated from the application implementation"
    },
    {
        "front": "What aspects of the runtime environment can be accessed by the device API of SAPUI5?",
        "back": "OS, Screen Size, Orientation Changes, Touch-Specific Features"
    },
    {
        "front": "You want to define a property with the name width to enhance a standard UI5 control. The property should hold the current width of the UI control. What is the best approach to defining the type of such a property?",
        "back": "Define property width with the type sap.ui.core.CSSSize"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true with regard to OPA5?",
        "back": "Can be used for user interaction tests, Can be used for SAPUI5 integration tests, Provides the possibility to test navigation, IS NOT a view controller test framework"
    },
    {
        "front": "To what namespace is the ExtensionPoint class assigned?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core NOT sap.ui.core.extension derp"
    },
    {
        "front": "Using S/4HANA 1610 with ABAP 7.51, which of the following templates can you use for SAP Fiori elements?",
        "back": "List Report, Object Page, Overview Page, NOT ALP"
    },
    {
        "front": "In Which use cases is a local annotation better than a CDS annotation?",
        "back": "Complex UI relevant annotations, You want to use annotations which are not supported by your current ABAP Version, (annotations is for 1 field IS NOT a correct selection )"
    },
    {
        "front": "Descriptions of search fields:",
        "back": "The search field is searching on more than one data field, there is only one search field per list report, Search field support fuzzy search"
    },
    {
        "front": "What steps need to be done in manifest.json if you need to hide variant function in a list report?",
        "back": "Add setting to enable smart variant management"
    },
    {
        "front": "The CDS annotation @UI.facet is used to create",
        "back": "a Header Facet, create a collection facet, which is displayed as a section and create a reference under collection facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "What can you do by editing manifest.json",
        "back": "Disable object page, Add objects pages as sub pages under an object page"
    },
    {
        "front": "Chart container 3 aggregations?",
        "back": "Content(Default), dimensionSelector, customIcons"
    },
    {
        "front": "What problem is solved by the list report floorplan?",
        "back": "you want to display a large collection of items and the user can take some action"
    },
    {
        "front": "What attribute is assigned to the @UI.fieldGroup to add an identifier?",
        "back": "Add property qualifier to field group and assign a unique identifier"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true when talking about SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "SAP Fiori is SAP user experience that applies modern-user centric design principles; SAP Fiori can be personalized, is simple and runs on any device; SAP Fiori provides a consistent and role-specific experience across all task for all lines of business"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following SAP Key UI technologies are currently recommended by SAP?",
        "back": "Web Dynpro with Screen Personas, Classical Screens with Screen Personas, SAPUI5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Fragment types SAPUI5?",
        "back": "JS,XML,HTML"
    },
    {
        "front": "Binding types supported in SAPUI5?",
        "back": "Property Binding, Aggregation Binding, Element Binding"
    },
    {
        "front": "Your customer wants to extend an SAP Fiori app through a Controller Extension. When can a controller extension lead to a crash?",
        "back": "If the original code required to run the application is overwritten. If the extension code accesses parts of the original application that were removed."
    },
    {
        "front": "what is an aggregation",
        "back": "is a parent child relationship, a relationship between the text field and its label"

    },
    {
        "front": "UI Annotations are stored within the ",
        "back": "metadata extensions file"
    },
    {
        "front": "The properties position within @UI.lineItem for list report controls",
        "back": "the order of columns within the list report table"
    }, 
    {
        "front": "How to make line item appear regardless of browser size",
        "back": "Set importance to #HIGH"
    },
    {
        "front": "Adding fields to filter bar with annotations",
        "back": "@UI.selectionField: [{position: 10}] FieldID;"
    },
    {
        "front": "Set entity header/table header for entity type/list report",
        "back": "@UI: { headerInfo: {typeName: 'Travel', typeNamePlural: 'Travels' } }"
    },
    {
        "front": "Metadata Annotation used to sort table",
        "back": "@UI.presentationVariant.sortOrder: [{ by: 'ElementID', direction: #DESC}]"
    },
    {
        "front": "applying sorting to list report table in Metadata annotation",
        "back": "@UI.presentationVariant.visualizations: [ { type: #AS_LINEITEM} ]"
    },
    {
        "front": "Define column label for a field in projection view",
        "back": "Under projection view, in the Data definition add field @EndUserText.label: 'Name'"
    },
    {
        "front": "What controls the source for content by reference shown in related field example in projection view - association",
        "back": "@ObjectModel.text.element: ['Source']"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you cast a sub-element or model object as another name in projection view? association",
        "back": "ex: Model _Agency: _Agency.Name as AgencyName"
    },
    {
        "front": "If you are using a UUID-based model for CDS view a ___ is required",
        "back": "semantic key, ObjectModel.semanticKey"
    },
    {
        "front": "Projection views contain the fields that can be shown on the UI. How can content be accessed from an entity that is defined externally?",
        "back": "By using an association"
    },
    {
        "front": "add a value help by defining ____ in _____ with ___",
        "back": "value help, projection view, @Consumption.valueHelpDefinition: [{ entity: [name: '/DATA/View', element: 'Key' ]}] "
    },
    {
        "front": "Create drop down for element in CDS View",
        "back": "@ObjectModel.resultSet.sizeCategory: #XS"
    },
    {
        "front": "Discover phase of the design thinking process",
        "back": "scoping, 360 research and synthesis"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design phase of the design thinking process",
        "back": "ideation, prototyping, validation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Deliver phase of design thinking process",
        "back": "developing, testing and deploying"
    },
    {
        "front": "tool for prototyping web apps using SAP Fiori UI elements or imported images of user interfaces",
        "back": "SAP Build"
    },
    {
        "front": "Help material for sap fiori",
        "back": "The help content for this user assistance is provided by the SAP Content Server hosted by SAP, an SAP Enable Now Manager hosted by the customer, or a mixture of both. "        
    },
    {
        "front": "Ommit key from column description text/display",
        "back": "In metadata extension file for lineitems add @UI.textArrangment: #TEXT_ONLY"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you add criticality to a field in listreport and what are the numbers to colors for criticality?",
        "back": "Add value criticality to @UI.lineItem as criticality, 2- yellow, 3- green, 1- red, 0- unknown state "
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the consequence if an additional field is defined within the CDS view of a draft-enabled application?",
        "back": "The related draft table has to be recreated using the quick-fix option in the behavior definitions file"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you set a field as the title for a business entity/object page in listreport?",
        "back": "Add @UI.headerInfo.title.value for the CDS view and reference it to the field"
    },
    {
        "front": "The CDS annotation @UI.facet is used to think object pages inside listreport",
        "back": "Create a Header Facet, Create a collection facet which is displayed as section, Create a reference under collection facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following properties are relevant to the type of facet?",
        "back": "purpose, type"
    },
    {
        "front": "If your back end system is based on ABAP 7.50, which are available ways of using facets?",
        "back": "Declare both field groups and facet as local annotation using BAS, Declare field group in CDS View declare facets as local annotation using BAS"
    },
    {
        "front": "What attribute is assigned to the @UI.fieldGroup to add an identifier?",
        "back": "Add property qualifier to field group and assign a unique identifier"
    },
    {
        "front": "Assigning properties to header facet for qualifier reference",
        "back": "@UI.datapoint for lineItem pointing using targetQualifier from facet in question"
    },
    {
        "front": "The CDS annotation @UI.facet is used to",
        "back": "Create a Header Facet, Create a collection facet which is displayed as section, Create a reference under collection facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Add a not header section to object page inside a listreport",
        "back": "Add a facet of type collection and use UI.Identification to reference the fields"
    },
    {
        "front": "add a item/facet to a collection inside @UI.facet",
        "back": "Reference the collection(defined in facet as #COLLECTION) by setting parentId value"
    },
    {
        "front": "A section in an object page is...",
        "back": "defined in a projection view file"
    },
    {
        "front": "A type in facets for defining one or more data fields in for example a object page",
        "back": "type #FIELDGROUP_REFERENCE in @UI.facet value referenced using @UI.fieldGroup with qualifier and position for item/at lineItem"
    },
    {
        "front": "Add table to object page in List Report(CDS)",
        "back": "Create UI facet of type LINEITEM_REFERENCE and add to data definition folder a metadata extension to create a list using @UI.lineItem definitons as in listreport"
    },
    {
        "front": "What determines the position of a column in a table (CDS)",
        "back": "The value of the property 'position' in the associated lineItem"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which steps in BAS provides the connection of the application to odata service when creating fiori elements apps",
        "back": "Data Source, and Service Selection"
    },
    {
        "front": "flexible column layout set in with BAS",
        "back": "Page map"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the page map used for",
        "back": "Showing the UI Structure of the application, Maintaining parameters to control the application behavior"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you make a List Report show data with out having to hit go on visit",
        "back": "Enable Initial Load"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the main reasons for using the SAP Fiori elements for OData v4 OPA test library?",
        "back": "You save a lot of time, You avoid repeatedly rewriting the same code, You keep your test up-to-date with central SAP Fiori elements framework changes"
    },
    {
        "front": "Where is mockdata stored in a Fiori elements project?",
        "back": "localService/mockdata in json"
    },
    {
        "front": "What file is started when you execute test from BAS SAP Fiori app?",
        "back": "test/integration/opaTests.quinit.html"
    },
    {
        "front": "File that imports page objects and OPA journeys you execute?",
        "back": "test/integration/Opa.qunit.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "How are opa journeys started?",
        "back": "With the JourneyRunner"
    },
    {
        "front": "opaTest funciton arguments",
        "back": "Given, When, Then"
    },
    {
        "front": "in an OPA Journey how is the application started?",
        "back": "With function iStartMyApp()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Why is the application used by the tests started within SAP Fiori Launchpad?",
        "back": "To be able to use shell functions like navigating back from objectpages"
    },
    {
        "front": "Various run scripts for npm stored in a Fiori project",
        "back": "in package.json under 'scripts'"
    },
    {
        "front": "url to trigger opaTests",
        "back": "/webapp/test/integration/opaTests.qunit.html"
    },
    {
        "front": "namespace for OPA tests",
        "back": "sap.fe.test"
    },
    {
        "front": "making additional checks with OPA Journey",
        "back": ".and.iTest({\"check\": \"this\"})"
    },
    {
        "front": "Load filter data into the list report table with OPA",
        "back": "iChangeFilterField('item', 'filterdat').and.iExecuteSearch()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Why wouldnt you use the test function iExecuteAction() for pressing go in a list report?",
        "back": "There are specific actions for triggering SAP Fiori elements standard actions, I would use test function iExecuteSearch(), since it is easier to use and no params have to be passed to the function."
    },
    {
        "front": "four blocks of sap fiori launchpad",
        "back": "Header, Anchor bar, Groups, Footer(optional)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Launchpad url",
        "back": "/sap/bc/ ui5_ui5/ui2/ushell/shells/abap/FioriLaunchpad.html"
    },
    {
        "front": "Launch pad abap transaction/cache buster",
        "back": "/sap/bc/ui2/flp"
    },
    {
        "front": "By default transaction /UI2/FLP starts the FLP via ICM, an entery can be added in table ____ that can be used to call a reverse proxy, such as web dispatcher.",
        "back": "HTTPURLLOC"
    },
    {
        "front": "What version of business client dropped NetWeaver from the name?",
        "back": "SAP Business Client 6.0"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ Mobile application for Apple iOS integrated with SAP S/4HANA and further SAP solutions, leveraging ____ The SAP Launchpad service, Notification service, and Mobile Services of BTP work together to provide web sites and apps for mobile usage. SAP Mobile Start integrates with mobile operating system features like notifications, spotlight search, and widgets running on smartphones, watches, and tablets.",
        "back": "SAP Mobile Start, SAP BTP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Personalization settings can be accessed through the",
        "back": "User Actions Menu"
    },
    {
        "front": "Settings that can be changed in Personalization settings",
        "back": "Theme Selection, Home Page and Language settings, Activation of user profiling, Maintenance of default values,  Appearence and behavior of notificatiosns"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tiles are organized in ___ in the (FLP) system",
        "back": "Catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "To show a tile in the FLP, it must be embedded in a",
        "back": "group"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ can be created centrally in the system and then added to the launchpad, or user can create an own ____ and add tiles from catalogs",
        "back": "groups, group"
    },
    {
        "front": "Introduced in SAP S/4HANA 2020 the __ can be used as an alternative to groups in the homepage",
        "back": "spaces"
    },
    {
        "front": "A ___ is visualized as a ribbon or tab at the top of the ___ and defines a frame for one or more pages",
        "back": "space"
    },
    {
        "front": "A ___ consists of sections showing tiles in the same way as groups have done before.",
        "back": "page"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ are an integral part of pages and can also be created by the user in their launchpad",
        "back": "sections"
    },
    {
        "front": "You can activate spaces where",
        "back": "in FLP settings under Spaces"
    },
    {
        "front": "You can transport home page and application personalization data to another system. The ____ report allows you to collect the personalization data and writes these to transport requests.",
        "back": "/UIF/MIGRATE_FES_PERSO"
    },
    {
        "front": "An ____ connects the FLP with the app implementation in the system. This includes starting the correct app with the correct parameters and the information shown on the tile.",
        "back": "app descriptor"
    },
    {
        "front": "Both _____ and _____ can then be assigned to user roles. This works similar to adding transactions to user roles and grants the user role access to all apps of the ____.",
        "back": "catalogs, groups, catalog"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Fiori theme that came about with SAP Fiori 3",
        "back": "SAP Quartz"
    },
    {
        "front": " All fact sheet and object page apps, as well as many other apps, offer the possibility to save the app status and visualized data as a tile in the FLP for later access.",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which element has the application as target",
        "back": "SAP Fiori app descriptor"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is meant by the term data-driven navigation",
        "back": "Data objects offer navigation links to dependent data objects and functions."
    },
    {
        "front": "When it comes to the design of user interface, one tool handles all technologies:",
        "back": "the UI Theme Designer"
    },
    {
        "front": "The SAP Conversational Artificial Intelligence (CAI) is a combination of SAP CoPilot and the startup formerly known as _____. CAI enables users to smoothly interact with SAP software through one unique conversational interface. The skills of conversational agents are built, trained, generated, and connected using ______.",
        "back": "Recast.AI, the Bot Builder"
    },
    {
        "front": "The only SAP Fiori app that uses HTML is the _______, which provides a frame for the XML-based views.",
        "back": "SAP Fiori launchpad"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which SAPUI5 versions are available on an Application Server ABAP is provided via ________.",
        "back": "https://<host>:<port>/sap/public/bc/ui5_ui5/index.html"
    },
    {
        "front": "The version a running app is using is visible in ",
        "back": "the technical information dialog opened via CTRL+ALT+SHIFT+P"
    },
    {
        "front": "Development environment on SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP), Neo environment supporting for example SAP Fiori, SAP S/4HANA Cloud, SAP HANA, SAP Mobile Services including programming languages such as SAPUI5, Java, and Node.js.",
        "back": "SAP Web IDE Full Stack"
    },
    {
        "front": "Native development environment for SAP HANA provided by SAP HANA Extended Services Advanced including programming languages such as Java and Node.js.",
        "back": "SAP Web IDE for SAP HANA"
    },
    {
        "front": "Local development environment for SAP Fiori and SAPUI5, which can be downloaded on https://tools.hana.ondemand.com/.",
        "back": "SAP Web IDE Personal Edition"
    },
    {
        "front": "_________ is the only IDE not supporting SAPUI5",
        "back": "SAP Web IDE for SAP HANA"
    },
    {
        "front": "Developing an SAP Fiori web app means developing SAPUI5 using the built-in support in SAP Web IDE or the ____ in BAS or VS Code.",
        "back": "SAP Fiori tools extension"
    },
    {
        "front": "Reverse invoke connection client to SAP BTP, uses SSL VPN connection",
        "back": "Cloud Connector"
    },
    {
        "front": "a connector attached to an SAP back-end system translates between ABAP APIs and OData entities",
        "back": "SAP Gateway"
    },
    {
        "front": "Enhance OData by adding additional information like dictionary labels.",
        "back": "SAP Annotations"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData is also extensible. This enables SAP to supplement the data types used by OData with extra information from the",
        "back": "ABAP Data Dictionary."
    },
    {
        "front": " SAP Gateway supports OData V2 since ____ and OData V4 since ______",
        "back": "AS ABAP 7.00,AS ABAP 7.50."
    },
    {
        "front": "The entities of an OData service are defined in an ______. _______ define properties and navigations to other entity types. ",
        "back": "Entity Data Model (EDM), Entity types"
    },
    {
        "front": " provides a single entry point to access business data of ABAP-based systems such as the SAP Business Suite or the SAP S/4HANA. _______ has the same role in SAP HANA. ",
        "back": "SAP Gateway, The SAP HANA Extended Applications Services (XS)"
    },
    {
        "front": "The transaction _____ offers a list of all registered OData services in the system. Complete maintenance of these services is possible here.",
        "back": "SAP Gateway Service Maintenance (/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE)"
    },
    {
        "front": "3 areas of /IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE transaction",
        "back": "Service Catalog, ICF nodes, System Aliases"
    },
    {
        "front": "For services not connecting to other systems, the Processing Mode is set ____ and _____ system alias is assigned.",
        "back": "to Co-deployed only and no "
    },
    {
        "front": "The SAP Gateway Service Administration for OData V4 consists of two transactions",
        "back": "/IWBEP/V4_ADMIN defines service groups, which are published using transaction /IWFND/V4_ADMIN"
    },
    {
        "front": " The first productive OData V4 service in SAP Gateway ______.",
        "back": "is the notification service for the SAP Fiori launchpad."
    },
    {
        "front": "What app type uses enterprise search capabilities of SAP HANA to provide search results?",
        "back": "Fact Sheet Apps"
    },
    {
        "front": "transactional available elements apps",
        "back": "overview page, list report, worklist"
    },
    {
        "front": "analytical available elements apps",
        "back": "overview page,analytical list page"
    },
    {
        "front": "factsheet elements apps",
        "back": "Overview Page, Object Page"
    },
    {
        "front": "BW Query used for analytical apps",
        "back": "Analytics Cloud, Design Studio, Web Dynpro ABAP"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the app ID of a transaction?",
        "back": "Transaction code"
    },
    {
        "front": "acts as a UI framework for organizaing multiple cards on a single page",
        "back": "overview page"
    },
    {
        "front": "cards on an overview page can deliver, ___,___, or ___",
        "back": "transactional, analytical, search data"
    },
    {
        "front": "The most common transactional SAP Fiori element is the ",
        "back": "list report"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP GUI transactions since SAP S/4HANA 1610",
        "back": "SAP Fiori apps reference library, now an official part of SAP Fiori, limited to transactions targeting enduser"
    },
    {
        "front": "Since sap fiori 2.0 Web Dynpro ABAP applications",
        "back": "Exclusive SAP HANA DB and SAP S/4HANA 1610 or later in SAP Fiori apps reference library"
    },
    {
        "front": "Role based insight into real-time operations of your business by collecting and displaying key figures directly in your browser",
        "back": "Analytical Apps"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Studio SAP Fiori Apps",
        "back": "Use similar technology in Business Warehouse as tool design studio, pregenerated for customers without use of KPIs, can be generated using SAPUI5 or Web Dynpro/FPM as UI tech"
    },
    {
        "front": "can change or create data found via search directly in app without opening other applications, changes are performed in place",
        "back": "Object pages"
    },
    {
        "front": "Do not have tiles delivered by sap, task for customizing or configuration, or user when saving search result as tile",
        "back": "Fact sheet and object pages"
    },
    {
        "front": "offers recommendations for SAP Fiori apps by analyzing the usage of an already existing system landscape",
        "back": "SAP Fiori reference library, using analysis started with Get SAP Fiori App Recommendations, needs usage and some system profiles as input"
    },
    {
        "front": "A list of the most used transaction in a system, can be collected based on end-user feedback or by tracing the used transactions in the system",
        "back": "usage profile"
    },
    {
        "front": "Transaction Workload Monitor, can be used to get usage profile",
        "back": "ST03"
    },
    {
        "front": "A list of installed software components in an SAP system.",
        "back": "system profile"
    },
    {
        "front": "LMDB",
        "back": "Landscape Management Database, can be used to analyze sap system and generate system profile"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the central frame application of SAP Fiori",
        "back": "SAP Fiori Launchpad"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is used as container for SAPUI5 apps in the ABAP repository?",
        "back": "Business Server Pages BSP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Where are the services for SAPUI5 apps organized?",
        "back": "ICF, Internet Communication Framework"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is JSON",
        "back": "Format defintion to structure data transferred using web technologies"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which OData option grants access to the service defintion?",
        "back": "$metadata"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which apps are meant by the term classic applications?",
        "back": "ABAP Transactions and Web Dynpro ABAP applications"
    },
    {
        "front": "The front end system in SAP Fiori Landscape",
        "back": "AS ABAP 7.50 or higher"
    },
    {
        "front": "The backend server in SAP Fiori Landscape",
        "back": "SAP S/4HANA or SAP Business Suite"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP FLP is able to communicate with FES directly but it is recommended to use ___ or another reverse proxy",
        "back": "SAP Web Dispatcher"
    },
    {
        "front": "Embedded deployment landscape",
        "back": "HTTPS/OData -> BES: Product UI, Central UI, SAP Gateway, S/4HANA/ABAP Implementation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Central Hub Deployment landscape",
        "back": "HTTPS/OData-> FES: Central UI, Product UI, SAP Gateway -> Trusted RFC -> BES: SAP Gateway, ABAP implementation "
    },
    {
        "front": "transaction SAP Gateway",
        "back": "SAP_GWFND"
    },
    {
        "front": "transaction Product UI",
        "back": "UIS4HOP1"
    },
    {
        "front": "Transaction Central UI",
        "back": "SAP_UI"
    },
    {
        "front": "Common ABAP implementations",
        "back": "S/4HANA"
    },
    {
        "front": "The only componenet in FES and BES",
        "back": "SAP Gateway"
    },
    {
        "front": "Recommended deployment option for SAP Business Suite",
        "back": "Central Hub Deployment"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mandatory components of FES",
        "back": "SAP Gateway for OData communication, Central UI for SAP Fiori functions, and Product UIs for apps"
    },
    {
        "front": "To use any SAP Fiori app a running ___ is needed",
        "back": "FLP"
    },
    {
        "front": "There is no communication to the BES by FLP, all general settings for SAP Fiori are saved in the FES to be independent from the BES",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAPUI5 apps are saved in _____ as ___ and delivered using product specific UI add-ons, these are installed on the FES.",
        "back": "ABAP repository, BSPs"
    },
    {
        "front": "The registration of the Gateway Services is performed on ___ by ___",
        "back": "FES, the customer"
    },
    {
        "front": "When Transactional apps need data,an Odata request is performed via the SAP Web Dispatcher to ",
        "back": "the registration of the Gateway service on the FES, from there the SAP Gateway service creates an RFC request to SAP Gateway service on the BES, ABAP code is used to access the data in the database"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ applications are part of the BES solution and have no interaction with the FES besides the FLP iself",
        "back": "Classic"
    },
    {
        "front": "When using SAP Workflow in SAP Fiori 1.0 the add-on _____ is needed in the FES",
        "back": "IW_PGW"
    },
    {
        "front": "When using data models of the Generic Interaction Layer (GENIL) the add on ____ is  needed in the BES",
        "back": "IW_GIL"
    },
    {
        "front": "when using Service Provider Infrastructure (SPI) ____ is neede",
        "back": "IW_SPI"
    },
    {
        "front": "A Gateway service consist of ______ and ____ in the FES,and a  _____ in the BES",
        "back": "ABAP classes, Customizing elements, service catalog entry"
    },
    {
        "front": "The ABAP classes seperate into two _____ that provide the code for the service meta data and two ____ that provide the code to handle service request",
        "back": "Model Provider Classes(MPC), Data Provider Classes(DPC)"
    },
    {
        "front": "All SAP Gateway transactions are connected to each other via _____",
        "back": "forward navigation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Central SAP Gateway service management in the FES",
        "back": "Sap Gateway Maintenance (/IWFND/MAINT_SERVICE)"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Gateway service test environment in the FES",
        "back": "SAP Gateway Client(/IWFND/GW_CLIENT)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Central SAP Gateway development environment in the BES",
        "back": "Sap Gateway Service Builder (SEGW)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Central ABAP development environment in the BES",
        "back": "ABAP Workbench(SE80)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Services provided by SAP HANA Platform",
        "back": "Application, Processing, Integration, Database"
    },
    {
        "front": "Provides tools for administration and monitoring of SAP HANA db  resources and for development capabilities through the SAP HANA explorer. Can be used to start and stop services, to monitor the system, to configure system settings and to manage users and authorizations",
        "back": "SAP HANA Cockpit"
    },
    {
        "front": "In most cases SAP recommends the _____ deployment for SAP S/4HANA",
        "back": "embedded"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ views are the basis for all analytical applications in S4H, abled to integrate with SAP S/4HANA embedded analytics, which originated from SAP Business Warehouse",
        "back": "ABAP CDS(Core Data Services)"
    },
    {
        "front": "There is no need to access data views via SAP HANA XS in the SAP BSP when using ___",
        "back": "ABAP CDS Views"
    },
    {
        "front": "Core element of SAP Smart business is the ___",
        "back": "KPI"
    },
    {
        "front": "is built on top of ABAP CDS Views and define evaluations, tiles and drilldowns",
        "back": "KPI"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ is in place as next generation of central app in SAP Smart Business",
        "back": "Manage KPIs and Reports[f2814]"
    },
    {
        "front": "since SAP S/4HANA 1511 the ____ is the central app for managing KPIs",
        "back": "KPI Workspace[F0818]"
    },
    {
        "front": "app can be started to actually deffine a query handling dimesnion, tables and charts, the result can be saved as a tile to access the query directly in the SAP FLP",
        "back": "Custom Analytical Queries[F1572]"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Enterprise Search, successor to SAP Netweaver enterprise search uses Protocol used for direct network communication, parrelels to OData but specialized for search requests and responses",
        "back": "SAP Proprietary Information Access(inA) protocol"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Gateway search service, if reggistered all search request for SAP Fiori search are routed through this service.",
        "back": "ESH_SEARCH_SRV"
    },
    {
        "front": "Important transactions that work both on SAP Search and Classfication(TREX, used by SAP Netweaver enterprise search) and SAP HANA enterprise search",
        "back": "ESH_COCKPIT, ESH_MODELER, ESH_TEST_SEARCH, ESH_IMG"
    },
    {
        "front": "for connectors of search models to the search engine",
        "back": "Connector Administration Cockpit(ESH_COCKPIT)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Modeler for search and analytic for managing search object connector models",
        "back": "Search and Analytics Modeler (ESH_MODELER)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Test environment for enterprise search, checking consistency of connectors and search results",
        "back": "Enterprise Search Test(ESH_TEST_SEARCH)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Area of the implementation guide containing administration and configuration of enterprise search",
        "back": "Search and Operational Analytics Implementation Guide(ESH_IMG)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Removing unwanted search objects/duplicates",
        "back": "For both classic search objects and CDS View-based search objects, you can deactivate the matching search connector in transaction ESH_COCKPIT, For CDS View searches only, you can deactivate the matching search connector in SAP Fiori app F3036 Manage Search Models,  ESH_DASHBOARD."
    },
    {
        "front": "If you encounter a duplicate search connector what might be the cause?",
        "back": "where you see “duplicate” searches it’s usually where a new CDS View search model has been introduced to replace the older classic search option."
    },
    {
        "front": "When using ABAP CDS Views, there is no need to access search connectors directly via InA such as in the SAP Business Suite.",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Users of the SAP Fiori launchpad may activate a personalized search in the FLP settings under _______. After activation, all search requests of the user in the SAP Fiori search are logged and made available via the _____.",
        "back": "User Profiling, My Queries [F3719] app"
    },
    {
        "front": "These defaults for collecting user-specific data can be managed via _____.",
        "back": "the Configure Personalized Search [F2800] app."
    },
    {
        "front": "deployed as stored procedures in SAP HANA",
        "back": "ABAP Managed Database Procedures"
    },
    {
        "front": "ABAP CDS Views on Hana",
        "back": "SAP HANA Views"
    },
    {
        "front": "CDS Views are developed using",
        "back": "ABAP Development Tools (ADT) in Eclipse"
    },
    {
        "front": "CDS Views are stored in ____, and can only be viewed using ______ in the SAP GUI",
        "back": "ABAP repository, transaction SE80"
    },
    {
        "front": "AMDPs are developed using ____, and can only be viewed using ____ in SAP GUI.",
        "back": "Eclipse ADT, transaction SE80"
    },
    {
        "front": "a global class method containing SQLScript as the programming language.",
        "back": "AMDP"
    },
    {
        "front": "The set of SQL extensions for the SAP HANA db that allow developers to push data intensive logic into the database is called _____",
        "back": "SQLScript"
    },
    {
        "front": "AMDPs can be identified by the syntax __ behind the method name",
        "back": "BY DATABASE PROCEDURE FOR HDB LANGUAGE SQLSCRIPT"
    },
    {
        "front": "Classes containing AMDPs implement the marker interface ____",
        "back": "IF_AMDP_MARKER_HDB"
    },
    {
        "front": "in the SAPUI5 development environment you can enrich the UI definition by adding annotations in the _____ or by _____",
        "back": "annotation.xml, mapping page config files"
    },
    {
        "front": "The ____ as part of SAP BAS are recommended tool for developing SAP Fiori elements artificats on UI-Level",
        "back": "SAP Fiori tools"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which system holds the SAP Fiori Launch pad in hub deployment",
        "back": "The FES"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which system component is split between front-end server and back-end server?",
        "back": "SAP Gateway"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which ABAP repository element contains the service logic?",
        "back": "DPC(Data Provider Class)"
    },
    {
        "front": "How is the implementation of SAP Fiori apps delivered by SAP?",
        "back": "Updates of the back-end server"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which data processing capabilities does SAP HANA combine?",
        "back": "Analytical and transactional"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which system part provides the analytical data in SAP S/4HANA?",
        "back": "SAP S/4HANA Embedded Analytics"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the data source defintion for the SAP Fiori search?",
        "back": "Search connectors"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the data source definition for object pages?",
        "back": "ABAP CDS View"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is used in S/4HANA to read data from databases?",
        "back": "ABAP CDS"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is used in SAP S/4HANA to run native code on the database?",
        "back": "AMPD ABAP Managed Database Procedures"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ catalogs define apps per solution area",
        "back": "Technical"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ catalogs reference these apps per duty of the user.",
        "back": "Business"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ can only be defined in configuration",
        "back": "Technical"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ catalogs can be defined in configuration and customizing",
        "back": "business"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ can be defined for configuration(cross-client), customizing(client-specific) and personailzation(user)",
        "back": "groups"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ and ____ are defined in customizing and ar changable in personalization",
        "back": "spaces, pages"
    },
    {
        "front": "______ roles are assigned to users in customizing",
        "back": ""
    },
    {
        "front": "Can handle configuration and customizing of groups, technical and business catalogs alike",
        "back": "SAP Fiori launchpad designer"
    },
    {
        "front": "ABAP Transaction for roles available for decades",
        "back": "PFCG"
    },
    {
        "front": "ABAP transaction for business catalogs avialable since SAP_UI 7.53",
        "back": "FLPCM"
    },
    {
        "front": "ABAP Transaction for technical catalogs available since SAP_UI 7.55",
        "back": "FLPAM"
    },
    {
        "front": "App for spaces available since SAP_UI 7.55",
        "back": "Manage Launchpad Spaces"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP Fiori launchpad app for pages availalble since SAP_UI 7.55",
        "back": "Manage Launchpad Pages"
    },
    {
        "front": "Since SAP_UI 7.55 the ______ role includes all tools for maintianing SAP Fiori.",
        "back": "SAP_FLP_ADMIN"
    },
    {
        "front": "The core two catalogs for maintaining SAP Fiori with SAP_FLP_ADMIN role",
        "back": "SAP_BASIS_BC_UI_FLA, SAP_BASIS_BC_UI_FLD"
    },
    {
        "front": "single role that replaces the SAP_UI2_ADMIN composit role",
        "back": "SAP_FLP_ADMIN"
    },
    {
        "front": "Catalogs, groups and spaces can be added to user roles using",
        "back": "The role maintenance transaction PFCG"
    },
    {
        "front": "If a newly created element is not available in the PFCG dialog box",
        "back": "restart the PFCG"
    },
    {
        "front": "sort the order of spaces in the FLP",
        "back": "via technical keys"
    },
    {
        "front": "When creating or changing a space, a custimizing ___ is mandatory",
        "back": "transport request"
    },
    {
        "front": "Every space has",
        "back": "ID(Customer space IDs must start with Z or Y and should contain abbreviation SP), description, title and at least one page"
    },
    {
        "front": "Every page has",
        "back": "ID(Customer space IDs must start with Z or Y and should contain abbreviation PG), description, title and at least one section"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sections are an integral part of pages and cannot",
        "back": "be reused in other pages"
    },
    {
        "front": "Sections group tiles by the _____",
        "back": "the level of dtails of a business task"
    },
    {
        "front": "It is also possible to select business catalogs manually in Manage Launchpad Pages. Hidden behind the ... button, all business catalogs can be selected as sources for tiles for the page. Tiles added in this way ___ ",
        "back": "will show the warning Out of role context and will not be displayed in the preview."
    },
    {
        "front": "The prerequisite for the user to see the tile in the FLP is that the corresponding business catalog is also part of the user master record. In other words",
        "back": "the source catalog of the tile must be assigned to any role also assigned to the user."
    },
    {

        "front": "______ known as standard catalogs provide app descriptors consisting of tiles and target mappings for web applications like SAPUI5",
        "back": "Technical Catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "Technical catalogs known as ______ or ______ provide app descriptors for classic applications like ABAP transactions originate from back-end servers.",
        "back": "replicable, backend catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "reference tiles and target mappings of Technical catalogs and Back end catalogs according to segregation of duty.",
        "back": "Business catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "Contain apps from various business catalogs making a subtopic",
        "back": "Business catalog groups"
    },
    {
        "front": "Combine multiple business catalogs and business catalog groups in one topic",
        "back": "Business roles"
    },
    {
        "front": "combine multiple pages into one topic",
        "back": "spaces"
    },
    {
        "front": "in sap business suite, replaces technical catalog roles and business catalog roles",
        "back": "Business roles"
    },
    {
        "front": "duty",
        "back": "business catalog"
    },
    {
        "front": "topic",
        "back": "business catalog group"
    },
    {
        "front": "end users role",
        "back": "Busniess role"
    },
    {
        "front": "introduced to ease mass-administration of catalogs",
        "back": "SAP Fiori Launchpad Content Manager (FLPCM)"
    },
    {
        "front": "can create/copy/check/transport catalog, reference tile and reference target mapping",
        "back": "FLPCM"
    },
    {
        "front": "can create/copy catalog, create group, create/reference tile, create/reference target mapping",
        "back": "FLPD"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tile: consist of title and subtitle, an icon, keywords for search and general information",
        "back": "App Launcher Static"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tile: can show dynamic number, number originates from odata service request, refresh interval can be set",
        "back": "App Launcher Dynamic"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tile: puprose show info from RSS(Really Simple Syndication) feeds, twice as large as other tiles, shows preview of feeds listed in tile definition, when selected shows all underlying elements of rss feeds",
        "back": "News tile"
    },
    {
        "front": "an intent consist of",
        "back": "semantic object, action"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which intent is called depends on",
        "back": "user role, same intent can lead to different results for different roles"
    },
    {
        "front": "contains information about what app to start, with what parameters and on what device types",
        "back": "Target mapping"
    },
    {
        "front": "represents a business entity such as a customer, a sales order, or a product",
        "back": "Semantic object"
    },
    {
        "front": "The central file of an SAP Fiori app based on SAPUI5 is",
        "back": "Component.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "To start an app(SAPUI5) the path to Component.js must be visible in statement",
        "back": "JQuery.sap.declare"
    },
    {
        "front": "In an embedded deployment all application types are allowed in ______ catalogs",
        "back": "technical"
    },
    {
        "front": "catalog type in central hub deployment, consist of SAPUI5 fiori apps, URL apps and tiles without target mapping in the frontend server",
        "back": "standard"
    },
    {
        "front": "catalogs that Consist of Web Dynpro ABAP apps, Webclient UI apps, and ABAP Transactions",
        "back": "Back end Catalogs in BES"
    },
    {
        "front": " Transaction ____ used in the FES to replicate back-end catalogs from BES as remote catalogs to the FES",
        "back": "/UI2/APPDESC_GET"
    },
    {
        "front": "For an ____ deployment, standard catalog is recommended as only catalog type",
        "back": "embedded"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mandatory fields app descriptor",
        "back": "semantic object, action, app type,one or more additional fields depending on app type"
    },
    {
        "front": "Tool for maintaining technical catalogs, offers list of technical catalogs and opens the FLPAM for the content of a single catalog, can create/delete and change catalog tiles",
        "back": "SAP Fiori Catalog Maintenance(/UI2/FLPCAT)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Is a kind of extraction of the app descriptors as tiles and target mappings in a remote catalog.",
        "back": "replication"
    },
    {
        "front": "A system alias for classic applications must be assigned to the back end cata log for replication to work",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Transaction to view System aliases for maintenance",
        "back": "/UI2/V_SYSALIAS"
    },
    {
        "front": "For each classica application an _____ and ____ destionation should be created in ___",
        "back": "RFC(alias_RFC), HTTPS(alias_HTTPS), SM59"
    },
    {
        "front": "Used to map aliases to target system aliases",
        "back": "/UI2/V_ALIASMAP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Transaction to define system aliases for customers",
        "back": "/UI2/VC_SYSALIAS"
    },
    {
        "front": "System alias assignments for back-end catalogs derived by SAP can be found in maintenance view _____ , where also customers can assign system aliases to their back-end catalogs",
        "back": "/UI2/V_ALIASCAT"
    },
    {
        "front": "Transaction: Replicates all back-end and replicable catalogs referenced in selected business catalogs.",
        "back": "/UI2/APPDESC_GET"
    },
    {
        "front": "Replicates all back-end and replicable catalogs for all system aliases",
        "back": "/UI2/APPDESC_GET_ALL"
    },
    {
        "front": "Replicates selected back-end and replicable catalogs for selected system alias",
        "back": "/UI2/APPDESC_GET_DEV"
    },
    {
        "front": "How many spaces should be assigned to a business role according to best practices",
        "back": "one"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which tool provides the definition of SAP Fiori groups?",
        "back": "SAP FLPD"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the prerequisite for a user to see the tiles of a group?",
        "back": "The catalogs containing the tile definitons are part of the user master record"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which element groups SAP Fiori apps based on solution area?",
        "back": "Technical Catalog"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which element groups SAP Fiori apps based on business duty?",
        "back": "Business Catalog"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is used to maintain technical catalogs?",
        "back": "SAP FLP application manager"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is meant by the term app descriptor?",
        "back": "Combination of tiles and target mappings in standard, replicable and back-end catalogs"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which catalog type must be set to enable back-end catalog maintenance in SAP Fiori Launchpad application manager?",
        "back": "None"
    },
    {
        "front": "What needs to be assigned to back-end catalogs for the replication to a front-end server?",
        "back": "System alias for classic applications"
    },
    {
        "front": "Transaction ____ offers many task list for a wide variation of technical configuration task in an ABAP system.",
        "back": "STC01"
    },
    {
        "front": "Task-list runs are logged in transaction ____",
        "back": "STC02"
    },
    {
        "front": "Technical setup for SAP Gateway, SAPUI5, and SAP Fiori Launchpad in one client, makes it posible to start SAP FLP",
        "back": "SAP_GW_FIORI_ERP_ONE_CLNT_SETUP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Initial setup for SAP FLP and SAP Fiori apps in SAP S/4HANA, makes it possible to use all features of SAP Fiori",
        "back": "SAP_FIORI_FOUNDATION_S4"
    },
    {
        "front": "Content activation for business roles shipped by SAP, makes it possible to use SAP Fiori apps defined in the business role",
        "back": "SAP_FIORI_CONTENT_ACTIVATION"
    },
    {
        "front": "Activates the content of business roles created by customers",
        "back": "SAP_FIORI_FCM_CONTENT_ACTIVATION"
    },
    {
        "front": "Define customer settings for FLP",
        "back": "/UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF"
    },
    {
        "front": "The semantic object for the FLP",
        "back": "Shell"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the starting point for activating apps with rapid activation for SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Business roles"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the foundation role shipped by SAP for SAP Fiori users",
        "back": "SAP_FLP_USERS"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is missing in the foundation roles?",
        "back": "Authorizations"
    },
    {
        "front": "What needs to be created to enable FLP customizing per role?",
        "back": "A business catalog with a target mapping holding the customizing"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the name space for SAP Gateway front-end transactions?",
        "back": "/IWFND/"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ manages the themes in the theme repository of an SAP NetWeaver Application Server ABAP. Themes can be viewed, imported, exported, and deleted, as well as transported to the follow-up system. This is also the easiest way to get a URI pointing to a certain theme. Start the tool using the following transaction: _______",
        "back": "The Theme Tool,/UI5/ THEME_TOOL."
    },
    {
        "front": "By adding the URI parameter ______, which points to the theme repository, to the application URI, the theme is used as the design for the application. This is available to all clients but stays visible in the URI.",
        "back": "sap-theme=<theme-id>@<theme-root>"
    },
    {
        "front": "Central them parameter setting transaction SAP Enterprise portal and AS ABAP",
        "back": "/UI2/NWBC_CFG_CUST per client, /UI2/NWBC_CFG_SAP client independent"
    },
    {
        "front": "Since SAP S/4HANA 2020, the parameter _______ is available to set the theme in ________. In addition the parameter _____ hides all themes provided by SAP only showing customer-specific ones in the FLP-settings.",
        "back": "THEMING_DEFAULT_THEME,/UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF, THEMING_HIDE_SAP_THEMES"
    },
    {
        "front": "The ABAP Development Tools (ADT) define a project for connecting to the repository of an ABAP system. A CDS view is saved as part of a data definition in the ABAP repository. To extend a CDS view, a CDS view extension must be created in the customer namespace referencing the original CDS view.",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": " the CDS View extension refers to the original CDS view using the syntax __________.",
        "back": "extend view <view_name> with <extension>"
    },
    {
        "front": "new sap bas based: ________ is a WYSIWYG editor to preview the application, make changes to the properties of controls, add code fragments, extend with controller, and see a list of changes that had been made.",
        "back": "The SAPUI5 Visual Editor"
    },
    {
        "front": "Plugins have the following characteristics:",
        "back": "Loaded automatically when FLP starts, implemented as a SAPUI5 component, implemented in a platform-independent way, Configured client-wide or assigned to roles"
    },
    {
        "front": "Developing a plugin involves the following steps",
        "back": "Implementing the plugin, Activating and configuring the plugin"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ for BTP offers an extension called SAP Fiori Launchpad Plugin, main component of this extension is a template to create an SAP Fiori Launchpad Plugin",
        "back": "SAP Web IDE Full-Stack"
    },
    {
        "front": "Generally, there are no views in a plugin. All changes to the FLP are defined by accessing ______",
        "back": "the renderer of the FLP in the Component.js file."
    },
    {
        "front": "Every plugin must be defined in transaction ______ before it can be used in the FLP. The plugin needs an _________ similar to other SAPUI5 applications.",
        "back": "/UI2/FLP_CONF_DEF,FLP Plugin ID as well as the component ID and URL (ICF path)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which system environments offer the UI Theme designer?",
        "back": "SAP Enterprise Portal, SAP Netweaver Application Server ABAP, SAP BTP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which design template is used for SAP Fiori 3",
        "back": "SAP Quartz"
    },
    {
        "front": "Where are themes saved for the SAP Fiori launchpad?",
        "back": "Theme repository in front-end server"
    },
    {
        "front": "How do you enter the UI Adaptation mode of SAP Fiori apps?",
        "back": "Start app-> User Action Menu-> Adapt UI"
    },
    {
        "front": "which tool must be used to extend CDS Views?",
        "back": "ADT for Eclipse"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is used to extend the SAP Fiori launchpad?",
        "back": "SAPUI5 plugins"
    },
    {
        "front": "How can you activate an extension for SAP Fiori launchpad?",
        "back": "Customer Settings(/UI2/FLP_CUS_CONF), Target Mapping(/UI2/FLPD_CUST)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Two types of crossplatform development approaches mobile development",
        "back": "SAP Mobile Cards - scriptbased development for card UIs, MDK - metadata-based application development platform"
    },
    {
        "front": "______ is a feature within SAP Mobile Services. It provides customers access to a micro app platform to publish data into a consumer grade “wallet” or “passbook” style app. Using ________, companies can create simple, yet highly valuable quick-win apps.",
        "back": "SAP Mobile Cards"
    },
    {
        "front": "The SAP Mobile Cards app is available for",
        "back": "iOS, android"
    },
    {
        "front": "The generic client for running MDK apps on Apple iOS and Google Android is the _________ ",
        "back": " SAP Mobile Services Client."
    },
    {
        "front": "he SAP Mobile Services for SAP Business Technology Platform (BTP) serves as a middleware to enhance communication for mobile applications and provide additional features in apps. Such a middleware is called a",
        "back": "Mobile Application Development Platform (MADP)"
    },
    {
        "front": "The _____ was the on-premise solution of SAP for a Mobile Application Development Platform (MADP) and the precursor of the SAP Mobile Services. The ____ is no longer available and maintenance ended in 2020.",
        "back": "SAP Mobile Platform (SMP)"
    },
    {
        "front": "MDK web apps are deployed as HTML5-apps in the SAP BTP and can be accessed in web browsers",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "What can be used as middleware to improve SAP Fiori for mobile",
        "back": "SAP Mobile Services"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the SAP Fiori for iOS guidelines based on?",
        "back": "HIG Apple Human Interface Guidelines"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is SAP BRP SDK assistant for iOS",
        "back": "Plugin for Apple Xcode to create ready-to-run Xcode projects for SAP Fiori"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP BTP provides following environments:",
        "back": "Cloud Foundry, Kyma, ABAP, New environment"
    },
    {
        "front": "environment is a fully managed Kubernetes runtime based on the open-source project ___ that allows developers to extend SAP solutions with serverless functions and combine them with containerized microservices.",
        "back": "Kyma"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is SAP BTP",
        "back": "SAPS PaaS providing in-memory database and application services"
    },
    {
        "front": "What establishes a secure connection between on-premise systems and SAP BTP?",
        "back": "Cloud Connector"
    },
    {
        "front": "How is the system landscape called when SAP BTP is only providing the SAP FLP, no business data",
        "back": "Internal Access Point"
    },
    {
        "front": "What combines tile and target mapping the SAP LP service",
        "back": "app"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which system part provides the OData services for analytical apps",
        "back": "SAP HANA extended application services(xs)"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the data source defintion for the SAP Fiori search?",
        "back": "search connectors"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is needed to define a target mapping for a Web Dynpro ABAP application?",
        "back": "System alias, Web Dynpro application, Web Dynpro configuration"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is needed to define a target mapping for an ABAP Transaction?",
        "back": "Transaction Code, System alias"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which tool is used in an SAP Business Suite environment to model KPI",
        "back": "KPI Modeler"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which part of a KPI is responsible for the visualization?",
        "back": "Drill-down"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is used as a container for SAP Fiori in an Enterprise Portal",
        "back": "SAP Fiori iView"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the central app to display Workflow items in SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "My Inbox"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which systems is the SAP Gatweay workflow service implemented?",
        "back": "Front-End Server (FES)"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is SAP Screen Personas?",
        "back": "A web-based layer for adaptation of SAP GUI Dynpro and Web Dynpro ABAP"
    },
    {
        "front": "What created with SAP Screen Personas to change the structure of classical screens?",
        "back": "Flavors"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP HANA extended application services (XS), which offers _____ based on data views in SAP HANA. ",
        "back": ".xsodata-files"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP HANA XS provides the _______ that you can use to build and test development artifacts in the SAP HANA environment. ",
        "back": "SAP HANA Web-based Development Workbench"
    },
    {
        "front": "tools provided and URL of SAP HANA Web-based Development Workbench",
        "back": "Catalog, Editor, Security, Traces, http://<HANAsystem>:<port>/sap/hana/ide"
    },
    {
        "front": "To navigate to the generic drill-down app in SAP Business Suite, the user needs the target mapping with semantic object _____ and action ______ .",
        "back": "* and action analyzeSBKPIDetails"
    },
    {
        "front": "To navigate to the generic drill-down app in SAP S/4HANA 1511, the user needs the target mapping with semantic object ___ and action ____",
        "back": "* and action analyzeSBKPIDetailsS4HANA"
    },
    {
        "front": "To navigate to the generic drill-down app since SAP S/4HANA 1610, the user needs the target mapping _______ generated when creating a tile for the KPI. It is saved in the same catalog as the tile",
        "back": "automatically"
    },
    {
        "front": "The tiles had different names in the first version of the KPI Modeler. Numeric was called Point Value, Comparison was called Deviation, and Actual vs. Target was called Contribution. Only Trend did not change.",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": " you can configure the appearance and functions of the FLP header bar by with the _____ URL option.",
        "back": "sap-ushell-config"
    },
    {
        "front": "my inbox: Map decision to outcom container value",
        "back": "/IWWRK/ES_WF_WI_BEFORE_UPD_IB"
    },
    {
        "front": "my inbox: Change subject in query result",
        "back": "/IWPGW/ES_TGW_TASK_QUERY"
    },
    {
        "front": "my inbox: Modify task title and task description",
        "back": "/IWPGW/ES_TGW_TASK_DATA"
    },
    {
        "front": "my inbox: modify user details",
        "back": "/IWPGW/ES_TGW_USER_DETAIL"
    },
    {
        "front": "All SAPUI5 resources are available on the content delivery network _____. There, you can also find multiple SAPUI5 versions, and you can reference them in your application.",
        "back": "Akamai"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ is the only IDE not supporting SAPUI5.",
        "back": "SAP Web IDE for SAP HANA"
    },
    {
        "front": "The Cloud Connector must not be used with products other than SAP Business Technology Platform or SAP S/4HANA Cloud. (t/f)",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "ABAP connection destinations",
        "back": "HTTP, Mail, RFC, LDAP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Location IDs provides advanced connection option where",
        "back": "multiple cloud connectors for one subaccount"
    },
    {
        "front": "Connection ABAP to consume OData from SAP BAS, property ______ and usage options with this destination:",
        "back": "WebIDEUsage, odata_abap, dev_abap"
    },
    {
        "front": "WebIDEUsage option: For OData functionality of SAP Gateway, corresponding to URL path: /sap/opu/odata",
        "back": "odata_abap"
    },
    {
        "front": "WebIDEUsage option: For extensibility scenarios and developing or deploying to an SAPUI5 ABAP repository, corresponds to url path:/sap/bc/adt",
        "back": "dev_abap"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cloud Connector: Destination configuration wait time",
        "back": "HTML5.Timeout"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cloud connector, remote system resides behind firewall, proxy type",
        "back": "OnPremise"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cloud Connector: HTML5 Applications runtime allows this destination to be used dynamically on the host or path level",
        "back": "HTML5.DynamicDestination: true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cloud connector: Expose the destination to the SAP BAS",
        "back": "WebIDEEnabled: true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Start portable variant of cloud connector",
        "back": "go.bat"
    },
    {
        "front": "Monitor cloud connector",
        "back": "In Connectivity section of SAP BTP Cockpit"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cloud connectors uses ____ for access control",
        "back": "strict white-list"
    },
    {
        "front": "deployment configuration file for sapui5 application and can be generated with",
        "back": "ui5-deploy.yaml, npx fiori add deploy-config"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following parameters must you provide when you create an initial cloud connector configuration?",
        "options": {"A": "Region","B": "Display Name","C": "Subaccount","D": "Password","E": "Location ID", "F": "Description"},
        "back": ["A","C","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Standard bootstrap file for sapui5",
        "back": "sap-ui-core.js"   
    },
    {
        "front": "benefits loading SAPUI5 from CDN",
        "back": "Loading SAPUI5 from a CDN improves your app performance; you can load from a server that (in most cases) is much closer to your location, and you can benefit from the caching mechanism and the language fallback logic."
    },
    {
        "front": "boot strap sapui5 <script> tag",
        "back": "<script id=\"sap-ui-bootstrap\" src=\"resources/sap-ui-core.js\" data-sap-ui-libs=\"sap.m\" data-sap-ui-theme=\"sap_fiori_3\" data-sap-ui-resourceroots='{\"student00.sap.training.helloworld\": \"./\"}'></script>" 
    },
    {
        "front": "script attribute prefix sapui5",
        "back": "data-sap-ui-"
    },
    {
        "front": "single attribute for config information(script, sapui5) instead of attaching individual options",
        "back": "data-sap-ui-config"
    },
    {
        "front": "global configuration object/attribute name sapui5 scripttag",
        "back": "sap-ui-config"
    },
    {
        "front": "can you add configuration parameters to url for sap",
        "back": "yes, ex index.html?sap-ui-debug=true"
    },
    {
        "front": "accessing runtime configuration object with method(sapui5/js)",
        "back": "sap.ui.getCore().getConfiguration()"
    },
    {
        "front": "You can display controls in HTML element called UI area by invoking the ____ method(ther can be ____ UI area(s)",
        "back": "placeAt(), multiple"
    },
    {
        "front": "Designed to support real Asynchronous Module Definitions(AMDs)",
        "back": "sap.ui.define(), sap.ui.require()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Synchronous loading of modules was possible using _____, declaring a module was possible with _____, beginning with SAPUI5 ver ___ both of these functions are depracated",
        "back": "jQuery.sap.require(),jQuery.sap.declare,1.52"
    },
    {
        "front": "Can use relative path of dependency in sap.ui.define with ./ ?",
        "back": "yes/true"
    },
    {
        "front": "A library preload file _____ contains all modules of a certain library. These modules will only be executed ____",
        "back": "library-preload.js, ondemand if the application requires them"
    },
    {
        "front": "An application must not reference the library-preload.js, if preload files exist, sapui5 automatically loads them",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "preload configuration parameters",
        "back": "async,sync, auto"
    },
    {
        "front": "set to true to enable async loading",
        "back": "data-sap-ui-async"
    },
    {
        "front": "the ____ method of the core registers a given function that is executed after the framework has been initialized.",
        "back": "sap.ui.getCore().attachInit()"
    },
    {
        "front": "using configuration option _____, it is possible to redirect the request for the application specific modules to the corresponding web application.",
        "back": "sap-data-ui-resourceRoots"
    },
    {
        "front": "asynchronous view instantiation factory method",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.mvc.<Type>View.create(mOptions):Promise, and generic factory sap.ui.core.mvc.View.create(mOptions):Promise"
    },
    {
        "front": "When a promise is pending, it can transition to the ____ or ___ state, once it is ____ or ____ it will never transition to any other state, and its value or failure reason will not change.",
        "back": "fullfilled, rejected"
    },
    {
        "front": "3 states of a promise",
        "back": "Pending, Fulfilled, Rejected"
    },
    {
        "front": "primary way of interacting with a promise is through its ____ method, which registers callbacks to recieve either a promises eventual value or reason why the promise cant be fullfilled.",
        "back": "then()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Two arguments for then",
        "back": "callback for success and callback for failure"
    },
    {
        "front": "configuration object properties, view instantiation",
        "back": "id,viewName, type"
    },
    {
        "front": "Controller defined by extending _____ object of the SAPUI5 core.",
        "back": "Controller e.g Controller.extend()"
    },
    {
        "front": "lifecycle hooks controller",
        "back": "onInit()(first render), onExit(), onAfterRendering(), onBeforeRendering()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Two default methods for the implementation of a JavaScript view",
        "back": "getControllerName, createContent"
    },
    {
        "front": "When reusing Javascript views there is gaurenteed ____ you _____ use hardcoded IDs",
        "back": "uniqueness, hardcoded"
    },
    {
        "front": "XML View options",
        "back": "xmlns:namespace, xmlns, controllerName"
    },
    {
        "front": "HTML view: All view-specific properties can be added to the <template> tag as ____ attributes",
        "back": "data-*"
    },
    {
        "front": "JSON: you add child controls as ____, everything child of ____",
        "back": "arrays, content aggregation"
    },
    {
        "front": "embedding views in XML view",
        "back": "<mvc:(JSView|XMLView|HTMLView|JSONView) id=\"idView\" viewName\"sap.training.view.MyView\"/> "
    },
    {
        "front": "Which function is provided to register a URL prefix for a module name prefix?",
        "back": "JQuery.sap.registerModulePath()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Layout: used to bring multi controls into one column, each control is placed below the other",
        "back": "sap.ui.layout.VerticleLayout"
    },
    {
        "front": "Layout: spacing between controls not adjustable(can be added with css), way to place controls side-by-side, forces all controls to be on one line without wrapping by default",
        "back": "sap.ui.layout.HorizontalLayout"
    },
    {
        "front": "Layout: flexible layouts, linebreaks, large, medium and small sized screens, responsive table free layouts, variable column amount of children based on screensize",
        "back": "sap.ui.layout.Grid"
    },
    {
        "front": "grid layout option: screens greater than 600 px and smaller than 1024 px",
        "back": "Tablet(\"medium\")"
    },
    {
        "front": "grid layout option: screens smaller than 600 px",
        "back": "Phone(\"small\")"
    },
    {
        "front": "grid layout option: For screens greater than or equal to 1024 px and smaller than 1440px",
        "back": "Desktop(\"large\")"
    },
    {
        "front": "grid layout option: for screens greater than or equal to 1440 px",
        "back": "LargeDesktop(\"extra large\")"
    },
    {
        "front": "device/grid layout size information API Reference",
        "back": "sap.ui.Device.media.RANGESETS"
    },
    {
        "front": "order grid layout values must be provided in",
        "back": "extra large, large, medium, small"
    },
    {
        "front": "gridlayout specifier format",
        "back": "<layoutData><l:GridData indent=\"M4\" span=\"L2 M8 S12\"/></layoutData>"
    },
    {
        "front": "the ____Layout expands the added content to fit a whole line, if window is resized controls are moved between the lines and resized again",
        "back": "ResponsiveFlow"
    },
    {
        "front": "The width of all ResponsiveFlowLayout elements should be set to ___%",
        "back": "100"
    },
    {
        "front": "Each ResponsiveFlowLayout element has a weight relative to other elements within a row, if one element has the weight 2 and all others have 1, the element is ___ the size of others.",
        "back": "double"
    },
    {
        "front": "Should Form layout be used for mobile user interfaces?",
        "back": "yes"
    },
    {
        "front": "To explicitly switch between Edit Mode and Navigation Mode from within a field in Form Layout press __",
        "back": "F2"
    },
    {
        "front": "A Form aggregates _____ to separate form content into different blocks",
        "back": "FormContainer"
    },
    {
        "front": "A FormContainer aggregates ______ A _____ combines form fields with a label.",
        "back": "FormElement(s)"
    },
    {
        "front": "If hCells is set to ____, the size is determined by the number of fields and the available cells. For Labels, the automatic size is 3 cells.",
        "back": "auto"
    },
    {
        "front": "Setting the additional property ____ to true for a column also reacts to the minScreenWidth you specify. In such a case, the column shows as a pop-in on smaller screens, instead of being completely hidden.",
        "back": "demandPopin"
    },
    {
        "front": "If an SAPUI5 application is running on a mobile device, a platform attribute is added to the HTML tag, which provides information about the current platform and version. In addition, the SAPUI5 adds a platform-dependent CSS class to the HTML tag of the page. ex",
        "back": "<html data-sap-ui-os=\"iOS9.1\" [...] class=\"sap-ios [...]\">... <html data-sap-ui-os=\"Android6.0\" [...] class=\"sap-android [...]\">"
    },
    {
        "front": "The default design for all controls belonging to the sap.m library is the ____",
        "back": "Cozy Density"
    },
    {
        "front": "if your application combines controls belonging to different libraries, we strongly recommend that you set the CSS class ____ if you want to use Cozy Density ",
        "back": "sapUiSizeCozy"
    },
    {
        "front": "the SAP Fiori launchpad (FLP) optionally reads the supported Content Densities from ________ and, if available, sets the appropriate Content Density class on the body tag.",
        "back": "the app descriptor (manifest.json)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Client side model(s)",
        "back": "JSON,XML,Resource"
    },
    {
        "front": "Server side model(s)",
        "back": "OData"
    },
    {
        "front": "Adding data to json model",
        "back": "setData(), loadData()"
    },
    {
        "front": "The resource model only supports ___ binding mode because it deals with static text only",
        "back": "one-time"
    },
    {
        "front": "Default binding mode for JSON Model",
        "back": "two-way"
    },
    {
        "front": "Default binding mode for XML Model",
        "back": "two-way"
    },
    {
        "front": "Default binding mode for OData Model",
        "back": "one-way"
    },
    {
        "front": "to set the default binding mode use method",
        "back": "setDefaultBindingMode()"
    },
    {
        "front": "allows properties of the control to get automatically initialized and updated from model data",
        "back": "Property binding"
    },
    {
        "front": "Can be used to automatically create child controls according to model data",
        "back": "Aggregation Binding"
    },
    {
        "front": "Allows to bind UI elements to a specific object in the model data, which will create a binding context and allows relative binding within the control and all of its children, This is especially helpful in master/detail scenarios",
        "back": "Element Binding"
    },
    {
        "front": "Binding that requires defintion of a template, which is cloned for each bound entry of the model.",
        "back": "Aggregation binding"
    },
    {
        "front": "Simple types available for data binding in SAPUI5",
        "back": "Integer, Float, String, Boolean, Date, Time, DateTime, Currency, FileSize"
    },
    {
        "front": "Function Simple Type: Called when the user modifies a value in the UI and the change is transported back into the model, May throw ParseException in the case where the value cannot be converted",
        "back": "parseValue()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Called in the case of successfull parsing to check additional constraints, like minimum or maximum value, May throw ValidateException in the case where constraints are violated.",
        "back": "validateValue()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Called when the value in the model is changed to convert it to the type of the control property to which it is bound, may throw a format exception.",
        "back": "formatValue()"
    },
    {
        "front": "String validation constraints",
        "back": "string, integer/float, boolean, maxLength, minLength, startsWith, startsWithIgnoreCase, endsWith, endsWithIgnoreCase, contains, equals, search"
    },
    {
        "front": "Data type does not have any format options",
        "back": "string"
    },
    {
        "front": "The use of styles _____ instead of pattern for Date type is preferred, as it automatically uses a locale-dependent date pattern.",
        "back": "short, medium, long or full"
    },
    {
        "front": "Format options supported by Date type",
        "back": "pattern, UTC, style"
    },
    {
        "front": "Validation constraints supported by Date",
        "back": "maximum, minimum"
    },
    {
        "front": "layout custom type implementation",
        "back": "extend/inherit simpletype, implement methods formatValue(), parseValue(), validateValue()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Available capabilities handling incorrect user input",
        "back": "attachFormatError(), attachParseError(), attachValidationError(), attachValidationSuccess()"
    },
    {
        "front": "method used to visualize the state related to the input fields value, possible value states are Warning, Error, Success, None",
        "back": "setValueState()"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAPUI5 provided central management for messages, available globally by calling singleton",
        "back": "Message Manager, sap.ui.getCore().getMessageManager()"
    },
    {
        "front": "You can activate automatic message generation in componenet metadata or as a parameter when instantiating an component, ___ section of manifest.json file and for individual controls by registering controls in the Message Manager using the method _____",
        "back": "sap.ui5, sap.ui.getCore().getMessageManager().registerObject()"
    },
    {
        "front": "registers a managed object so that its parse and validation errors are handled by the Message Manager",
        "back": "registerObject()"
    },
    {
        "front": "filter operators available",
        "back": "BT,Contains, EndsWith, EQ, GE, GT, LE, LT, NE, StartsWith"
    },
    {
        "front": "Enable binding of multiple properties in different models to a single property of a control, work only from mode to view(read only)",
        "back": "Calculated fields"
    },
    {
        "front": "Resource Bundle files: Language suffixes are formed according the ____ locale syntax",
        "back": "JDK"
    },
    {
        "front": "Resource bundle file name format, UK english",
        "back": "i18n_en_UK.properties"
    },
    {
        "front": "A collection fo resource bundle files, all files are named with the same base name and an optional suffix that identifies the language contained in each file",
        "back": "Resource Bundle"
    },
    {
        "front": "IE returns the language of the OS installation as ____ and the language from the OS regional settings as ___",
        "back": "browserLanguage, userLanguage"
    },
    {
        "front": "by priority(last highest) source of Current Language Code/Locale in SAPUI5",
        "back": "Hard-coded UI5 default locale, Configured browser language, Configured user language, general language information, language contained in UA string, language configured in application, URL params"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hard-coded UI5 default locale",
        "back": "en"
    },
    {
        "front": "Configured browser language for IE OS language",
        "back": "window.navigator.browserLanguage"
    },
    {
        "front": "Configured user language, for IE the language in region settings",
        "back": "window.navigator.userLanguage"
    },
    {
        "front": "general language information from the browser",
        "back": "window.navigatot.language"
    },
    {
        "front": "Android languaged contained in UA string",
        "back": "window.navigator.userAgent"
    },
    {
        "front": "Configured locale in application coding",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.Configuration"
    },
    {
        "front": "setting language by URL parameters",
        "back": "sap-ui-language"
    },
    {
        "front": "If you need localized texts within your application you can use the JS module _____ to load the locale specific file from the server and access the texts within it",
        "back": "sap/base/i18n/ResourceBundle"
    },
    {
        "front": "to create an instance of sap/base/i18n/Resource bundle call ____, if no locale is passed the default locale is en, otherwise the locale is taken from the sapui5 configuration",
        "back": "ResourceBundle.create()"
    },
    {
        "front": "ResourceBundle: the create() method returns a new resource bundle or a ___ on that bundle in asynchronous cases",
        "back": "Promise"
    },
    {
        "front": "From SAPUI5 1.77 a list of supported locales can be specified to restrict number of locales for which resource bundles may be requested, this list is passed using parameter _____ if it is empty or not specified all locales are supported",
        "back": "supportedLocales"
    },
    {
        "front": "English used to be the default locale, but now any fallback locale can be specified using parameter _____, if not specified fallback defaults to en",
        "back": "fallbackLocale"
    },
    {
        "front": "Relationships between resources are hyperlinks between resources in the OData protocol",
        "back": "Hypermedia design pattern"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData: The resources are defined in an abstract data model that is based on the ____",
        "back": "Entity Data Model"
    },
    {
        "front": "There are twp types of documents associated with each OData service: ____ and ____",
        "back": "The Service Document, Service Metadata Document"
    },
    {
        "front": "Document that describes the data model, the structure, organization of all the resources exposed as HTTP endpoints by the service, and Provides a full description of the services interface",
        "back": "Service Metadata Document"
    },
    {
        "front": "Document declares the resources accessible from the Service Root URI",
        "back": "Service Document"
    },
    {
        "front": "Service metadata document can be retrieved by appending string ____ to the service root uri",
        "back": "$metadata"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ Describes the EDM for a given service using an XML language for describing models called _____",
        "back": "Service Metadata Document, Conceptual Schema Definition Language(CSDL)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Richly structured records with a key, structure provided by its properties",
        "back": "Entity Types"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ are instances of entity types and are grouped in entity sets",
        "back": "Entities"
    },
    {
        "front": "Structured types also consisting of a list of properties but no key, used to type the properties of entity types",
        "back": "Complex Types"
    },
    {
        "front": "Special properties on entity types that are bound to a specific association",
        "back": "Navigation properties"
    },
    {
        "front": "define the relationships between two or more Entity Types",
        "back": "Associations"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData services can expose ____ which are simple functions whose semantics are defined by the author of the function, can accept input and return entities or complex/primitive values",
        "back": "Service Operations"
    },
    {
        "front": "Create: ___, Read: ____, Update: ____, Delete: ____",
        "back": "POST,GET,PUT,DELETE"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData uses HTTP ____ for optimistic concurrency control. ___ can also be used for conditional GET request",
        "back": "ETags"
    },
    {
        "front": "Query string parameters a client may specify to control the amount and oder of the data that an OData service returns for the resource identified by the URI",
        "back": "System Query Options"
    },
    {
        "front": "List of important System Query options",
        "back": "Filtering: $filter, Projecting: $select, Sorting: $orderby, Paging: $top and $skip, Inlining: $expand"
    },
    {
        "front": "When processing a PUT request the server returns _____ to indicate success, there is no response body",
        "back": "HTTP status code 204(No Content)"
    },
    {
        "front": "If a delete opeation executed successfully the server returns ___ with no response body",
        "back": "HTTP Status Code 204 (No Content)"
    },
    {
        "front": "______ is a server-side model, meaning the dataset is only available on the server and the client only knows the currently visible(requested) data. Operations such as sorting and filtering are done on the server.",
        "back": "OData model"
    },
    {
        "front": "app changes when setup to use odata service",
        "back": "manifest.json updated property dataSources is added to the sap.app section including the URI to the selected OData service, OData model entry is added to models section, ui5.yaml and ui5-local.yaml proxy settings are added, a file named metadata.xml reflecting metadata service entities is added to localService folder"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ OData model instance can cover ____ OData service, To access Multiple services you have ____ model instances",
        "back": "one, one, to create multiple OData"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData Model Instance: Service URL can be passed as first parameter or within ___ map to the constructor",
        "back": "mParameters"
    },
    {
        "front": "The only mandatory parameter(s) when creating an ODataModel Instance is/are ____",
        "back": "the service URL"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ parameter allows the application to read associated entities with their navigation properties",
        "back": "expand"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ parameter allows the application to define a subset of properties that is read when requesting an entity",
        "back": "select"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData: to create entities for a specified entity set call the ____ method, returns a context object that points to the newly created entity",
        "back": "createEntry()"
    },
    {
        "front": "To store entities in the OData backend the application calls _____, to reset the changes the application can calle ______ method ",
        "back": "submitChanges(), deleteCreatedEntry(oContext)"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData HTTP ETags: The ETag can be passed within the parameters map for ____ CRUD request, if no ETag is passed the ETag of the _____ is used, if it is loaded already",
        "back": "every, cached entity"
    },
    {
        "front": "If XRSF token is no longer valid for an OData model the function _____ can be called, the token is fetched with request to the service document, eo ensure the reception of a valid toke ensure that the service document is not cached.",
        "back": "refreshSecurityToken()"
    },
    {
        "front": "All Odata operations have a mandatory _____ parameter as well as optional _____ map",
        "back": "sPath, mParameters"
    },
    {
        "front": "the create() function triggeres a ____ request to an OData service",
        "back": "POST"
    },
    {
        "front": "the read() function triggers a ___ request to a specified path(OData service)",
        "back": "GET"
    },
    {
        "front": "The update() function triggers a _____ request to the OData service, the update method used is defined by the global ______ parameter, which is ___ by default",
        "back": "PUT/MERGE, defaultUpdateMethod, sap.ui.model.odata.UpdateMethod.Merge"
    },
    {
        "front": "To send update request in a PUT request you must set the parameter defaultUpdateMethod to ____ when instantiating the OData model.",
        "back": "sap.ui.model.odata.UpdateMethod.Put"
    },
    {
        "front": "The remove() function triggeres a _____ request to the OData service",
        "back": "DELETE"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData Model: If you carry out a ___,____ or ____ function the model identifies the bindings and triggers a refresh for these bindings.",
        "back": "create, update, delete"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData model: You can disable auto refresh by calling _____",
        "back": "oModel.setRefreshAfterChange(false);"
    },
    {
        "front": "the ____ function refreshes all data within an OData Model. Data that has been imported using manual CRUD request is ____ automatically",
        "back": "refresh(), not reloaded"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ class is the base class for UI and faceless components.",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.Component"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mandatory component files",
        "back": "Component.js, manifest.json"
    },
    {
        "front": "To render UI Components you must wrap them in a _____",
        "back": "ComponentContainer"
    },
    {
        "front": "data attribute for  components within DOM",
        "back": "data-sap-ui-component"
    },
    {
        "front": "App descriptor: The ___ namespace contributes application specific attributes",
        "back": "sap.app"
    },
    {
        "front": "App descriptor: the ___ namespace contributes UI-specific attributes",
        "back": "sap.ui"
    },
    {
        "front": "App descriptor: the ___ name space contributes SAPUI5-specific attributes",
        "back": "sap.ui5"
    },
    {
        "front": "App descriptor: in the resources section of the ____ namespace, additional js and css resources for the component can be loaded.",
        "back": "sap.ui5"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ prevents verticle scrollbars appearing with Views that are set to 100% height",
        "back": "displayBlock=\"true\""
    },
    {
        "front": "To configure the router, add a ___ section to the ____ section in manifest.json",
        "back": "routing, sap.ui5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Default binding mode for OData v4 Model",
        "back": "Two-Way"
    },
    {
        "front": "Supported binding types OData v4",
        "back": "List, Context, Property"
    },
    {
        "front": "Supported events OData v4 Model",
        "back": "dataRequested, dataRecieved, patchSent, patchComplete"
    },
    {
        "front": "Available methods OData Model v4 context objects",
        "back": "getBinding, getIndex"
    },
    {
        "front": "to use service side filtering and server side sorting set the operation mode to ",
        "back": "sap.ui.model.odata.OperationMode.Server"
    },
    {
        "front": "list binding combines dynamic filter and static filter with logical ___",
        "back": "AND"
    },
    {
        "front": "Difference between function and actions for an OData service",
        "back": "functions must return data, and cant have a side effect, actions may return data and do have a side effect"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData: Request associated with Group ID ____ or _____ are bundled in one batch request which is triggered automatically before rendering",
        "back": "$auto, $auto.*"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData: Request associated with Group ID ____ are sent directly without batch",
        "back": "$direct"
    },
    {
        "front": "To specify group ID use paramaters for binding which triggers the request _____ for read request and ____ for update request",
        "back": "$$groupId, $$updateGroupId"
    },
    {
        "front": "The create() method returns the binding context, that context provides the ____ method which returns a Promise",
        "back": "created()"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAP BTP BAS Config: ___ for consuming odata, ____ for extending existing fiori apps, ____ for executing sapui5 apps",
        "back": "odata_abap, dev_abap, ui5_execute_abap"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the principle of SAP UX Strategy",
        "options": {"A": "Design Strategy", "B": "New Renew Enablement", "C": "New Renew Empower", "D": "Architecture and Technology", "E": "Sap Screen Personas"},
        "back": ["C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What impact does SAP Fiori have on business?",
        "options": {"A": "Digitalization", "B": "Simplification", "C": "Support the web and Open Standdards", "D": "Provides a user centered approach", "E": "Leads to re-imagination of processes"},
        "back": ["A","B","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the goals of the SAPUI5 framework?",
        "options": {"A": "Provide a user interface technology for building and adapting client applications", "B": "Provide a user interface technology for building and adapting server-based applications", "C": "Provide a lightweight programming model for desktop only applications", "D": "Provide an extensible framework for building desktop and mobile applications"},
        "back": ["A","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Discover phase",
        "back": "Scope, Research, Synthesize, Understand your end users needs"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Phase",
        "back": "Ideate, Prototype, Validate, Fail fast, fail Early, Sketch out solutions, getfeedback try again"
    },
    {
        "front": "Develop phase",
        "back": "Implement, Test, Deploy, Start development once user satisfaction is confirmed"
    },
    {
        "front": "/company/@name possible binding for XML view?",
        "back": "yes/true"
    },
    {
        "front": "@name info/employees/text() appropriate binding syntax?",
        "back": "yes"
    },
    {
        "front": "To get path information of selected item of model, use function ______",
        "back": "getBindingContext().getPath()"
    },
    {
        "front": "To use Expression Binding you need to enable Extended Binding Syntax via configuration setting _____ set to complex",
        "back": "xx-bindingSyntax"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____: Where user can bookmark places in an app, Do not require user to start at top of page and descend through multiple links just to get information from a specific page",
        "back": "Deep linking"
    },
    {
        "front": "Allows you to determin various runtime platform characteristics, stored in client-side JSON Model, Defined in component",
        "back": "sap.ui.Device"
    },
    {
        "front": "resource bundle config defined in ____ object of manifest.json file",
        "back": "sap.ui5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Master-Detail design pattern supported by ____ or ____ control",
        "back": "sap.m.SplitApp, sap.f.FlexibleColumnLayout"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ defines overall layout of application, root view instantiated at app start by the Component",
        "back": "App View"
    },
    {
        "front": "Store JS code in ___ folder, for code that needs to be reused accross multiple controllers, ex define a formater that can be used for data display",
        "back": "util"
    },
    {
        "front": "route with optional parameter",
        "back": "product/{id}/detail/:detailid:"
    },
    {
        "front": "route for mandatory pattern",
        "back": "prouduct/{id}"
    },
    {
        "front": "Defines a name, pattern and optionally one or more targets to which to navigate when has been matched",
        "back": "route"
    },
    {
        "front": "defines a view that is displayed, associated with on or more routes",
        "back": "target"
    },
    {
        "front": "if you do not specify a parameter for a target, a default value is taken from the config ___",
        "back": "section.ViewType"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: Different levels define navigation direction, lower level to higher level leads to forward navigation",
        "back": "viewLevel"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: The control that is used to display the view",
        "back": "controlId"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: target aggregation to which a view is added, eg NavContainer control has aggregation called Pages and shell container has content",
        "back": "controlAggregation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: a view created and added before target view is added",
        "back": "parent"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: where the view is located in the app",
        "back": "viewPath"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: where the control is located",
        "back": "targetParent"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets: specifies whether the aggregation should be cleared before adding the new view instance, when you use sap.m.routing.Router the default is false, for sap.ui.core.routing.Router it is true",
        "back": "clearAggregation"
    },
    {
        "front": "the router is configured using the _____ in the config customizing object in the ____",
        "back": "routerClass-property, routing-object"
    },
    {
        "front": "Routers are initialized in _____ ____ function",
        "back": "Component.js init"
    },
    {
        "front": "To access the router and to use its functions use ___ or the static ____ of the UI component, you can pass either a controller or a view",
        "back": "this.getOwnerComponent().getRouter() function, sap.ui.core.UIComponent.getRouterFor(this) function"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ method can be used in code for navigation to a defined route name",
        "back": "navTo()"
    },
    {
        "front": "parameters are passed with ___ handled in ____ to exchange data between views",
        "back": "navTo, attachRouteMatched"
    },
    {
        "front": "access configured targets using the _____ method",
        "back": "this.getRouter().getTarget(target)"
    },
    {
        "front": "navigation events are documented in the psuedo interface ___",
        "back": "sap.m.NavcontainerChild"
    },
    {
        "front": "the default routerClass is _____",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.routing.Router"
    },
    {
        "front": "Available transition animation types for navigation are",
        "back": "slide(default), flip, fade, show"
    },
    {
        "front": "onNavBack function navigates to previous has value in app history, if this is not present it navigates to ____",
        "back": "overview route"
    },
    {
        "front": "function navTo of router is invoked using the name of the route and a boolean parameter indicating if ____ should be created",
        "back": "browser history entry"
    },
    {
        "front": "mandatory query parameter for route",
        "back": "{?query}"
    },
    {
        "front": "optional query parameter for route",
        "back": ":?query:"
    },
    {
        "front": "Aggregation entites of sap.f.FlexibleColumnLayout",
        "back": "beginColumnPages, midColumnPages, endColumnPages"
    },
    {
        "front": "Control ____ handles correct visulization on different devices and screensizes using the letterboxing concept, contains the sap.m.App control",
        "back": "sap.m.Shell"
    },
    {
        "front": "Targets can also be displayed directly in an app without hitting a route",
        "back": "true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Components of sap.f.DynamicPage control",
        "back": "DynamicPageTitle, DynamicPageHeader, Content, Footer"
    },
    {
        "front": "if diplaying a sap.m.FlexBox with non-adaptive content set the _____ property of the flexbox to false",
        "back": "fitContainer"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object page layout",
        "back": "sap.uxap.ObjectPageLayout"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object page layout content structure",
        "back": "Header, Anchor Bar, Sections, Subsections, Blocks"
    },
    {
        "front": "wrapper object for Master view list in detail view",
        "back": "ListSelector"
    },
    {
        "front": "3 states of Promise in javascript",
        "back": "Pending, Fulfilled, Rejected"
    },
    {
        "front": "messages: (client side) refer to control; they are created from the input validation and by the application itself",
        "back": "UI messages"
    },
    {
        "front": "messages: refer to a binding path; they are managed by the server and are changed every time the back end responds to a request",
        "back": "Server Message"
    },
    {
        "front": "required anatomy of messages",
        "back": "ID, Type, Target, Message processor, Message Text"
    },
    {
        "front": "Message manager can be accessed by calling",
        "back": "sap.ui.getCore().getMessageManager()"
    },
    {
        "front": "You can activate automatic message generation in manifest.json with",
        "back": "sap.ui5.handleValidation: true or as parameter when instantiating Component data-handle-validation=\"true\""
    },
    {
        "front": "Activate automatic message creation for individual controls by",
        "back": "registering the control in the messagemanger, sap.ui.getCore().getMessageManager().registerObject(oInput,true)"
    },
    {
        "front": "add message manually to the message manager",
        "back": "oMessageManger.addMessage(new Message({}))"
    },
    {
        "front": "set message for odata error",
        "back": "\"error\": \"code\":\"\", \"message\":{\"lang\":\"en-US\", \"value\": \"Error message\"}}"
    },
    {
        "front": "Dialogs do not automatically inherit content density, to set content density same as parent use convenience function",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.syncStyleClass"
    },
    {
        "front": "Custom control and component libraries: library.js file calls the ____ method with an objec that describes the content of the library",
        "back": "sap.ui.getCore().initLibrary()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Custom control and component libraries: A normilized version of lib info can be returned with ",
        "back": "getLoadedLibraries()"
    },
    {
        "front": "Mandatory attributes for manifest.json of cutom library",
        "back": "id, type, applicationVersion"
    },
    {
        "front": "dependencies for custom library are defined in",
        "back": "manifest.json, sap.ui5.dependencies"
    },
    {
        "front": "find deployed UI library using transaction",
        "back": "sicf"
    },
    {
        "front": "call custom library with",
        "back": "data-sap-ui-resourceroots in index.html or JQuery.sap.registerModulePath"
    },
    {
        "front": "Agile Testing Pyramid: Unit Test",
        "back": "Qunit, Sinon"
    },
    {
        "front": "Agile Testing Pyramid: Component Test",
        "back": "OPA, Mock Server"
    },
    {
        "front": "Agile Testing Pyramid: System Tests",
        "back": "Selenium"
    },
    {
        "front": "Agile Testing Pyramid: Manual Tests",
        "back": "Exploratory Testing"
    },
    {
        "front": "Agile testing pyramid bottom to top",
        "back": "Unit, Component, System, Manual"
    },
    {
        "front": "testing: ____ is an object that you use to pass to the code under test, you can set expectations on it but cant be verified",
        "back": "a stub"
    },
    {
        "front": "testing: an object we can set expectations on and which will veryify the expected actions have indeed occured",
        "back": "a mock"
    },
    {
        "front":"testing: if you want to verify the behavior of a code under a test you use ___ with the approriate expectation and verify that. If you want to just pass a value that may need to act in a certain way, but is not the focus of this test you use a ___",
        "back": "mock, stub"
    },
    {
        "front": "A mocking framework for javascript that has the following features, provides support for spies, stubs and mocks, supplies higher-level test doubles for timers and AJAX requests, is included in SAP UI5 libraries",
        "back": "Sinon.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "Just like most unit test frameworks, Qunit follows an ____ pattern",
        "back": "arrange-act-assert"
    },
    {
        "front": "Qunit, validates true or false",
        "back": "ok(boolean, string)"
    },
    {
        "front": "QUnit defines a test",
        "back": "test(string, function)"
    },
    {
        "front": "QUnit, compares two values using double-equal",
        "back": "equal(value1,value2,message)"
    },
    {
        "front": "QUnit, compares two values based on their content, not just their identity",
        "back": "deepEqual(value1, value2, message)"
    },
    {
        "front": "QUnit: strictly compares two values using the triple-equal comparator",
        "back": "strictEqual(value1, value2, message)"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ only provide return values for method calls (indirect input) Mocks, never causes a test to fail",
        "back": "stub"
    },
    {
        "front": "mocks can be dynamically created using framework",
        "back": "Sinon.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "all test suites are collected in ____ ",
        "back": "AllJourneys.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "Test framework used for User Interaction tests, SAPUI5 Integration Tests, Navigation Tests, and DataBinding",
        "back": "OPA5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Objects provided by OPA5 tests and their place in arrange-act-assert",
        "back": "Given=arrangements, When=actions, Then=Assertions"
    },
    {
        "front": "When is the use of a master-detail pattern not recommended?",
        "back": "You need to offer complex filters for the master list of items, When you want to display different facets of the same object data or both"
    },
    {
        "front": "What message types are known to SAPUI5?",
        "back": "Control Message, Server Message"
    }, 
    {
        "front": "You want to define a property with the name width to enhance a standard UI5 control. The property should hold the current width of the UI control. What is the best approach to dfining the type of such a property?",
        "back": "Define the property width of the type sap.ui.core.CSSSize"
    },
    {
        "front": "What to do implementing your own control renderer?",
        "back": "You must implement a class that is derived from sap.ui.core.Renderer, the implementation should use the AMD syntax and it is also necessary to assign the renderer implementation to the renderer property of your UI control implementation."
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following aspects are true for SAPUI5 UI element",
        "options": {"A": "A UI element has an API", "B": "A UI element does not have a renderer", "C": "A UI element has a renderer", "D": "A UI element can have events"},
        "back": ["A","B","D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Does QUnit support SAPUI5 view tests?",
        "back": "No, UI tests must use OPA5"
    },
    {
        "front": "The file will be added by the standard SAP Fiori project templates or through the ____ -command of your SAP Business Application Studio. You can find the command in the command palette View → Find Command or CTRL+Shift+P.",
        "back": "Consume SAP Services"
    },
    {
        "front": "A good place and a common practice is to store the requested business data in a folder called _____ as a subfolder of the localService folder in the SAPUI5 project. The file name has to reflect _____ and the file type needs to be json.",
        "back": "mockdata, the name of the entity set"
    },
    {
        "front": "The most structured way using a local JSON-file is to implement a JavaScript function to the _____ file. The ______ file is located in the ____ of the SAPUI5-project.",
        "back": "model.js, model-folder"
    },
    {
        "front": "steps using mockserver",
        "back": "reference mockserver class, prepare metadata.xml fetch from service $metadata, get json data fetch $format=json, store locally in project"
    },
    {
        "front": "start application in simulation mode",
        "back": "start with a file in test, mockServer.html, data-sap-ui-onInit"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData: Defines whether to update all bindings after submitting this change operation. See set_____ If given, this overrules the model-wide ____ flag for this operation only.",
        "back": "refreshAfterChange"
    },
    {
        "front": "the ___ handles visual representation of SmartField Controls",
        "back": "field control"
    },
    {
        "front": "Available attributes for field control(SmartField Control)",
        "back": "Enable(Toggles from display to Edit), Visible(Hides the smartField control), Mandatory(Determines whether input is required)"
    },
    {
        "front": "For fields of type SmartFiield the SmartForm control automatically creates a label based on the ____",
        "back": "OData metadata annotations"
    },
    {
        "front": "A SmartForm control consist of: ",
        "back": "groups, groups elements"
    },
    {
        "front": "A collection of controls that are displayed along with a label, typically consist of exactly one control and the respective label(SmartForms)",
        "back": "group element"
    },
    {
        "front": "The SmartForm control aggregates groups and a group aggregates group elements, the group elements themselves aggregate elements of type ______",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.Control"
    },
    {
        "front": "Layout SmartForm control",
        "back": "ResponsiveGridLayout"
    },
    {
        "front": "overview page information is visualized in a ____, different __ for different types of content",
        "back": "card format, cards"
    },
    {
        "front": "Successor to the read only Factsheet is",
        "back": "Object Page"
    },
    {
        "front": "describe semantics related to data",
        "back": "annotations"
    },
    {
        "front": "UI-Annotations used in CDS-View are mapped to UI-controls and elements _____",
        "back": "at runtime"
    },
    {
        "front": "Where is the best place to store local data when using the SAP Business Application Studio",
        "back": "localService and mockdata folder"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following SAP Fiori element based UIs are currently available?",
        "options":{"A": "Wizard Form", "B": "List Report", "C": "Master-Detail", "D": "Overview Pages", "E": "Object Page" },
        "back": ["B", "D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "is a feature of SAPUI5 flexibility that allows key users without technical knowledge and developers to easily make UI changes in a WYSIWYG manner.",
        "back": "UI Adaptation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Extension points are only put into your ____ code",
        "back": "view, <core:ExtensionPoint name=\"extension_ux410\""
    },
    {
        "front": "Customization is based on the configuration of components. A special area of their configuration is dedicated to customization information. This configuration is located in a JavaScript file named ______",
        "back": "Component.js"
    },
    {
        "front": "The custom application becomes the ___ which launches the delivered standard application with the additional customizing configuration.",
        "back": "start-up project"
    },
    {
        "front": "App descriptor for application varient",
        "back": "manifest.appdescr_variant"
    },
    {
        "front": "in manifest, an customizing object is added under the extends object that is part of the ___",
        "back": "sap.ui5 object"
    },
    {
        "front": "onInit and onAfterRendering in the extension are called ____ onInit and onAfterRendering of the standard/original controller.",
        "back": "after"
    },
    {    
        "front": "onExit and onBeforeRendering in the extension are called ____ onExit and onBeforeRendering of the standard/original controller.",
        "back": "before"
    },
    {
        "front": "Extension points are only available for ___ code",
        "back": "view"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ are extension points in the controller code that are used to make controller extensions more stable.",
        "back": "Hooks"
    },
    {
        "front": "To what namespace is the ExtensionPoint class assigned?",
        "back": "sap.ui.core"
    },
    {
        "front": "What types of extensions/replacements are supported by SAPUI5?",
        "back": "View Replacement/Modification, Replace Service, Implement UI Controller Hooks"
    },
    {
        "front": "3 main states of a file in GIT",
        "back": "Committed, Modified, Changed"
    },
    {
        "front": "in which state are files in GIT when a remote repository is cloned",
        "back": "Staged and modified, Tracked and unmodified, Modified and tracked, When a remote GIT repository is cloned, all of the files are in the tracked and unmodified state."
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the result of a GIT Reset?",
        "back": "Returns the project back to the previous state"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the result of a GIT Revert?",
        "back": "Undoes a committed snapshot"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are true about the merge functionality of GIT?",
        "options": {"A": "A merge deletes the content of a branch", "B": "Allows the merging of two local branches into one local branch", "C": "Allows integration of a branch into another branch"},
        "back": ["C: Allows integration of a branch into another branch"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Design led development process",
        "back": "Discover, Design, Develop, Deploy"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAPUI5 compiles with ____ and can be used together with standard ___ libraries",
        "back": "OpenAjax, JavaScript"
    },
    {
        "front": "The SAPUI5 runtime is a client-side ____ rendering library with a ruch set of standard and extension controls",
        "back": "HTML5"
    },
    {
        "front": "Client-side model(s) intended for small datasets",
        "back": "XML, JSON"
    },
    {
        "front": "Server side model, sorting and filtering on client not possible",
        "back": "OData Model"
    },
    {
        "front": "Discover Phase",
        "back": "Scope, Research, Synthesize"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Phase",
        "back": "Ideate, Prototype, Validate"
    },
    {
        "front": "Develop Phase",
        "back": "Implement, Test, Deploy"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the current UI Technologies of SAP?",
        "back": "SAPUI5, Web Dynpro ABAP/Floorplan Manager, Dynpro"
    },
    {
        "front": "Annotations must grouped by ______. _____ associate a group of annotations to something in OData service. As most annotations are data relevant, they try to target an entity type or property.",
        "back": "Targets"
    },
    {
        "front": "Information part of term definition",
        "back": "Term Name, Data Type, Applies To, Nullable, Annotations to the term"
    },
    {
        "front": "If you have two annotations with the same term for the same target, a _____ must be added to make your annotation unique.",
        "back": "qualifier"
    },
    {
        "front": "Most terms are described by _____ type. A ______ type can have properties that are further described by _____",
        "back": "Complex, other complex types, or OData built in types (Edm.*)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Abstract type for all DataField* types, defines common properties to describe a field.",
        "back": "DataFieldAbstract"
    },
    {
        "front": "A normal data field on screen, displays values from a field of an entity type of the OData Service",
        "back": "DataField"
    },
    {
        "front": "Another annotation determines the field displayed on screen",
        "back": "DataFieldForAnnotation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Rendered as a button or link, the actual action is relevant to the value of the field",
        "back": "DataFieldWithAction"
    },
    {
        "front": "Rendered as a button or link, the action is not relevant to value of the field in contrast to DataFieldWithAction",
        "back": "DataFieldForAction"
    },
    {
        "front": "The data source of the field is a field in other entity types which can be accessed through an association",
        "back": "DataFieldWithNavigationPath"
    },
    {
        "front": "The data field is rendered as hyperlink and opens a URL when selected by the user",
        "back": "DataFieldWithURL"
    },
    {
        "front": "The data field is rendered as a hyperlink, jumps to an intent defined in SAP Fiori Launchpad, the target is relevant to value of the field",
        "back": "DataFieldWithIntentBasedNavigation"
    },
    {
        "front": "The data field is rendered as hyperlink, jumps to an intent defined in SAP Fiori Launchpad, The target is not relevant to the value of the field in contrast to DataFieldWithIntentBasedNavigation",
        "back": "DataFieldForIntentBasedNavigation"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ controls are SAPUI5 controls which can be rendered dynamically according to annotations of an OData Service",
        "back": "Smart"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ the predecessor of SAP Fiori Elements",
        "back": "Smart Template"
    },
    {
        "front": "Main Elements of list report",
        "back": "Application Header, Save as Tile, Smart Table, Footer Toolbar"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ as replacement of ALV in SAP GUI, Lots of ABAP Queries created by SQVI and ALV based ABAP Reports can be replaced by ____",
        "back": "List Report"
    },
    {
        "front": "A major entry of _____ is to select a row in list report, so this page is combined in List Report Template.",
        "back": "Object Page"
    },
    {
        "front": "Elements of an Object Page",
        "back": "Page Title, Object Header(Title and Subtitle, Editing Status Icon), Header Toolbar, Optional Elements: Image, Description, Buttons, Header Facets, Anchor Navigation area, Content Area, Footer Bar"
    },
    {
        "front": "Provides quick access to vital business information at a glance in the form of visual, actionable cards.",
        "back": "Overview Page"
    },
    {
        "front": "Overview Page application main components",
        "back": "Application header, Smart Filter, Cards"
    },
    {
        "front": "Analytical List Page introduced in SAP S/4HANA ____ and ABAP ____",
        "back": "1709, 7.52"
    },
    {
        "front": "Lets you analyze data from different perspectives, to investigate a root cause and to act on transactional content.",
        "back": "ALP"
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps to enable application from Netweaver ABAP",
        "back": "1. Open SAP Fiori Launchpad Designer and create a tile catalog for the application. 2. Create a target Mapping, expose application as an intent ( Semantic Object-Action ). 3. Create a tile based on the target mapping"
    },
    {
        "front": "Give user permissions to access a SAP Fiori Application, authorizations needed",
        "back": "Front End User: User must have a role which has the tile catalog in its role menu, Back End user: User must have authorization object to access the OData service and business data."
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps creating SAP Fiori Elements Application",
        "back": "1. Create an SAP Fiori elements application\n2. Choose an OData service.\n3. Create an annotation file and Writing annotation.\n4.Modify configuration file.\n5.Translate resource bundles.\n6.Deploy your SAP Fiori elements application.\n7. Configure SAP Fiori Launchpad.\n8. Authorize user to access SAP Fiori application.\n9. Log on to SAP FLP and add the tile to the SAP FLP"
    },
    {
        "front": "SADL",
        "back": "Service Adaptation Definition Language"
    },
    {
        "front": "Help you publish a group of associated CDS views to an OData service",
        "back": "SADL framework"
    },
    {
        "front": "Each CDS View is an ____ and their associations are translated to OData associations",
        "back": "Entity Set"
    },
    {
        "front": "Annotation for CDS View to generated an OData service in your back-end system",
        "back": "@Odata.Publish: true" 
    },
    {
        "front": "CDS Annotations are grouped by ____. Annotations with the same ____ stay together",
        "back": "target"
    },
    {
        "front": "OData annotations do not have a fixed position. It is usually grouped by ____",
        "back": "terms"
    },
    {
        "front": "When translated to an OData annotation, the sequence of CDS annotations belonging to one term is determined by a _____",
        "back": "position property"
    },
    {
        "front": "CDS: To seperate annotation from business logic use _____ extension",
        "back": "metadata"
    },
    {
        "front": "Use SADL if",
        "back": "Write annotation for the entire view, Write annotation for one field, Data intensive logic e.g. ValueHelp"
    },
    {
        "front": "Use local annotation if",
        "back": "Complex annotation not associated to particular field(ex. UI Facets), The annotation you want to use is not supported by current ABAP version, Backend server is not ABAP server(ex. AS Java, HANA)"
    },
    {
        "front": "Using SAP S/4HANA 1610 with ABAP 7.51, which of the following templates can you use for SAP Fiori elements?",
        "options": {"A": "List Report", "B": "Object Page", "C": "Overview Page", "D": "Analytic List Page"},
        "back": ["A","B","C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the limitations of publishing CDS as OData service by adding a @OData.publish:true",
        "back": "Cannot Change names of entity sets, Only 1 level is taken into consideration when exposing associations, No customized ABAP code in SAP Gateway"
    },
    {
        "front": "In which cases, is a local annotation better than a CDS annotation?",
        "back": "Complex UI relevant annotations, You want to use annotations which are not supported by your current ABAP version"
    },
    {
        "front": "@UI.lineitem.importance- Default Value, display in all clients",
        "back": "#HIGH"
    },
    {
        "front": "@UI.lineitem.importance- Only display in desktop browser or tablet",
        "back": "#MEDIUM"
    },
    {
        "front": "@UI.lineitem.importance- Only display in desktop browser",
        "back": "#LOW"
    },
    {
        "front": "CDS View and Columns: use ____ to hide fields you do not want to expose to end user",
        "back": "@UI.hidden"
    },
    {
        "front": "To add a search field for a list report, a developer must enable it on CDS View Level by adding a ____ annotation",
        "back": "@Search.searchable:true"
    },
    {
        "front": "For calculated fields in value help view use _____ to set a label",
        "back": "@EndUserText.label"
    },
    {
        "front": "Annotate the selection field with ____",
        "back": "@Consumption.valuehelp:'<association_name>'"
    },
    {
        "front": "Prerequisites for SAPUI5 flexibility service",
        "back": "Server ABAP front end and SAP NetWeaver 7.31 SP 11 or higher, Activate: /SAP/BC/UI5_UI5 & /SAP/BC/LREP, For shared variants: ABAP Autho object /UIF/FLEX authorization field /UIF/KEYU='X', Transport request with a task assigned to the user"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ stores filter conditions for users, after filtering data a user can save the condition as a variant",
        "back": "Selection Variant"
    },
    {
        "front": "Presentation Variant, ____",
        "back": "Table Variant store information about column list and order of the table"
    },
    {
        "front": "To combine presentation and selection variant into one ____ management can be used",
        "back": "smart variant"
    },
    {
        "front": "To enable smart variant management in manifest.json set ____ to true",
        "back": "in domain sap.ui.generic.app, set \"smartVariantManagement\": true"
    },
    {
        "front": "To disable variant management edit manifest.json with: _______",
        "back": "in sap.ui.generic.app, \"smartVariantManagement\":true, \"variantManagementHidden\":true"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of following description about search field is NOT true",
        "options": {"A": "The search field is searching on more than one data field", "B": "There is only one search field per list report", "C": "The search field searches for only one data field", "D": "Search field support fuzzy search"},
        "back": ["C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Avaialbe options for creating a value help for a selection field",
        "back": "By adding a foreign key annotation, By adding a value help annotation"
    },
    {
        "front": "What steps needs to be done in manifest.json if you need to hide variant function in a list report?",
        "back": "Add setting to enable smart Variant Management, Set setting variantManagementHidden to True"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object page: in body area, by default fields annotated with _____ display",
        "back": "@UI.identification"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object page: Indicates name of the business object",
        "back": "@UI.headerinfo.typeName"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Points to the ID data field",
        "back": "@UI.headerinfo.title.value"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object page: Like UI.LineItem, fields with this annotation displays in the General Information Section of the page",
        "back": "@UI.identification"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Facet displays a group of fields with a label",
        "back": "Field Group"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Facet displays description information from exactly one field",
        "back": "Plain Text"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Facet generates a hyper link, the user can access communication information(ex phon, mail, so on) by selecting the link.",
        "back": "Communication Facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Facet displays  micro chart to help the user get the most important KPI Information",
        "back": "Smart Micro Chart Facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Facet displays rating information as stars",
        "back": "Rating Indicator Facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: Facet displays a key figure or status information in different color or style to help user get the meaning at a glance",
        "back": "Data Point Facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object Page: to define a plain text header facet:",
        "back": "Define a field gorup containing only one field\nSet the field as a multiline text"
    },
    {
        "front": "Technically a communication header facet is a _____ header facet. Difference is at least one field of the field group should reference to a ____ annotation.",
        "back": "Field Group, vCard.Contact"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which types are supported as header facets for an object page?",
        "back": "Field Group Facet, Plan Text Facet, Rating Indicator Facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "The CDS annotation @UI.facet is used to",
        "back": "Create a Header Facet, Create a collection facet which is displayed as section, Create a reference under collection facet"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following properties are relevant to the type of facet?",
        "back": "purpose, type"
    },
    {
        "front": "If your back end system is based on ABAP 7.50, which are available ways of using facets?",
        "back": "Declare both field groups and facet as local annotation using BAS, Declare field group in CDS View declare facets as local annotation using BAS"
    },
    {
        "front": "If you want to display a list report without an object page, you can delete pages and all properties in it under _____",
        "back": "ListReport → <Your EntitySetName>."
    },
    {
        "front": "Under the ObjectPage node, you can add a ____ and add a subpage for each OData entity set.",
        "back": "pages sub node"
    },
    {
        "front": "Fiori elements options for external navigation",
        "back": "URL, Semantic object navigation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Options for semantic object navigation",
        "back": "Display as a link, use of a button in toolbar"
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps to create external navigation using a URL",
        "back": "Create a field represent as URL, add link, set type to #WITH_URL and point to the url field using url property"
    },
    {
        "front": "For navigation to semantic objects",
        "back": "Add a @consumption.semanticObject before field, set UI.lineItem.type to #WITH_INTENT_BASED_NAVIGATION or #FOR_INTENT_BASED_NAVIGATION, set @UI.lineItem.semanticObjectAction"
    },
    {
        "front": "format semantic object, action url",
        "back": "#SemanticObject-action?info=item&infomore=anotheritem"
    },
    {
        "front": "Criticality can be used for __",
        "back": "data field displayed on list report and object page, and other annotations with DataField as datatype like UI.fieldGroup and UI.identification"
    },
    {
        "front": "criticality to integer values",
        "back": "0-Neutral, 1-Negative, 2-Critical, 3-Positive"
    },
    {
        "front": "To prevent users from displaying criticality number directly ___",
        "back": "field should be set to hidden"
    },
    {
        "front": "Default colors for criticality status",
        "back": "Neutral=Black, Negative=Red, Critical=Yellow, Positive=Green"
    },
    {
        "front": "You can use the theme designer to change default criticality colors by adjusting the theme t/f",
        "back": "t"
    },
    {
        "front": "to use rating indicator or progress bar for fiori elements",
        "back": "set @UI.lineItem(also @UI.fieldGroup, @UI.identification and other annotations that are DataField) to type #AS_DATAPOINT, then add @UI.dtaPoint annotation and set visualization property to @RATING or #PROGRESS"
    },
    {
        "front": "By default rating indicator has ____ and progress bar is set to ____ as target, can customize those further by setting the value of _____",
        "back": "five stars, 100, targetValue property"
    },
    {
        "front": " A smart chart control sends an aggregate request to the back end service by sending ______ parameter",
        "back": "$select OData"
    },
    {
        "front": "To define an analytic entity set add a ____ annotations to fields you need to aggregate",
        "back": "@defaultAggregation"
    },
    {
        "front": "Another method of creating an analytic OData service is _____",
        "back": "Analytic Query"
    },
    {
        "front": "A ____ annotation is used to define a smart chart and is also available in local annotation",
        "back": "@UI.Chart"
    },
    {
        "front": "A reference facet should be created as a direct child of ____ with type ____ and reference to ____ annotation through an association",
        "back": "@UI.facet, #CHART_REFERENCE, @UI.Chart"
    },
    {
        "front": "BOPF",
        "back": "Business Object Processing Framework"
    },
    {
        "front": "one an object page you can make changes to Object like",
        "back": "Edit, Delete, switch between display and edit mode with Edit button"
    },
    {
        "front": "Object page with write capability: A database table is needed to store records, table must include structure _____",
        "back": "/bobf/s_lib_admin_data"
    },
    {
        "front": "In ____, a business object is represented as a hierarchial tree of nodes. A single node includes a set of semantically related attributes and corresponding business logic. For each node _____ type(s) of entity(ies) can be defined to describe the specific business logic part of the business object, you can generate ____ by adding annotations in the business objec CDS view.",
        "back": "BOPF,Several, BOPF"
    },
    {
        "front": "What steps are used to display a field as a rating indicator?",
        "back": "Set type of line item #AS_DATAPOINT, add a @UI.datapoint to the field and set visualization to #RATING"
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the differences between analytical entity set and normal entity set from an OData consumer perspective?",
        "back": "Analytical Entity Set: Generates a new field for primary key, returns all data needed to analyze client, analyzes the use of the database and runs faster when SAP HANA is used as database compared to a normal entity set"
    },
    {
        "front": "Main components of overview page (OVP)",
        "back": "Application header, Smart filter, Cards"
    },
    {
        "front": "Types of Cards",
        "back": "List Card, Bar Chart List Card, Link List Card, Analytic Card, Table Card, Quick View Card, Stack Card, Custom Cards"
    },
    {
        "front": "List cards display list of records according to config in ____ term, List Cards display up to __ fields of data in each list item.",
        "back": "com.sap.vocabularies.UI.v1.LineItem, six"
    },
    {
        "front": "Analytic cards let you view data in a variety of chart formats. The card is divided into two areas( ___ and ___)",
        "back": "header, chart"
    },
    {
        "front": "A table card displays a list of records according to configuration in _____ term. A table card displays data in a _____ layout. You can configure smart links in table cards to access quick links.",
        "back": "com.sap.vocabularies.UI.v1.LineItem, 3-column table layout"
    },
    {
        "front": "Stack cards, up to ____ can be displayed in the object stream",
        "back": "20 stacked cards"
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps to create an Overview Page",
        "back": "1. Prepare the backend service for a global filter.\n2. Prepare the back end service for cards.\n3. Create an SAP Fiori application using the Overview Page template\n4. Add cards for the Overview page."
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ is the recommended mode for all ALP based applications",
        "back": "Visual filter mode"
    },
    {
        "front": "Decimal precision, ___ only, Applications can influence via ____ connected to the visual filter",
        "back": "0 or 1, UI.DataPoint.NumberOfFractionalDigits"
    },
    {
        "front": "on load of ALP __ Batch calls for ___",
        "back": "3, 1 for visual filters, 1 for table and 1 for chart"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ extension: Developers can add extesnions during SAP Fiori elements-based apps using the Guided Development of SAP BAS and the extension API.",
        "back": "App"
    },
    {
        "front": "___ extensions: Customers and Partners introduce their own functionality to an existing app using Adaption project of SAP Business Application Studio to build their own upgrade-safe application variant",
        "back": "Adaption"
    },
    {
        "front": "Use securedExecution method whenever one of the following operations must be performed by extension coding:",
        "back": "- An asynchronous operation\n- An operation that needs to be synchronized with other operations that are potentially triggered by the user.\n- An operation that could result in losing the data entered by the user\n- Displaying custom messages to the user\n- Changing the title of the message popup after a quick action has been performed by the system."
    },
    {
        "front": "Use ___ to read the state of all custom fields and store that state in the object provided to enable the templates to use it for navigation.",
        "back": "getCustomAppStateDataExtension"
    },
    {
        "front": "Use ____ to get the custom app state object you provided in getCustomAppStateData and set the corresponding values for your custom controls, for example you call this method after returning from a navigation.",
        "back": "restoreCustomAppStateExtension"
    },
    {
        "front": "____ enables functions for different user groups to adapt SAPUI5 applications in a simple and modification-free way.",
        "back": "SAPUI5 flexibility"
    },
    {
        "front": "Minimum SAPUI5 version for adaptation projects",
        "back": "1.71"
    },
    {
        "front": "Adaptions added or configured in the visual editor are stored in ___ files",
        "back": ".change"
    },
    {
        "front": "Adaption: Use the __ tool to deploy a new application variant use as namespace parameter the namespace specified in the file _____ of your adaption project",
        "back": "yo, manifest.appdescr_variant"
    },
    {
        "front": "Adaption: If you want to hide the base application in general, add the URL parameter _____, with the namespace of your application variant to the target mapping of the base application.",
        "back": "sap-appvar-id"
    },
    {
        "front": "The accuracy and completeness with which specified users can achieve specified goals in particular environments",
        "back": "Effectiveness"
    },
    {
        "front": "The resources expended in relation to the accuracy and completeness of goals achieved",
        "back": "Efficiency"
    },
    {
        "front": "The comfort and acceptability of the work system to its users and other people affected by its use",
        "back": "Satisfaction"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is described as the persons perceptions and response that result from the use or anticipated use of a product, system or service?",
        "back": "User experience"
    },
    {
        "front": "What does effectiveness mean in the relation to the user interface?",
        "back": "The accuracy and completeness with which specified users can achieve specified goals in specific environments"
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following can be used for usability assessment?",
        "options":{"A": "Heuristic Evaluation", "B": "User Testing", "C": "User Observation", "D": "Questionaires"},
        "back": ["A", "B", "D"]
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Thinking: Innovate",
        "back": "Discover area of innovation, Design innovative solution, Develop Customer Solution"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Thinking: Empower",
        "back": "UX Center of Excellence, DT/Design Methods, UI Technology Training"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Thinking: Realize",
        "back": "Implement Standard Solution, Adapt Standard Solution, Optimize Existing Solution"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design Thinking: Advise",
        "back": "UX Strategey, UX Value Framework, UX Roadmap, UI Technology, Design Services"
    },
    {
        "front": "_____ apps for each role into granular, relevant tasks and activities",
        "back": "disaggregate"
    },
    {
        "front":"5 SAP Fiori principles",
        "back": "Role-Based, Adaptive, Simple, Coherent, Delightful"
    },
    {
        "front": "3 App types",
        "back": "Transactional: Task-Based Access, Analytical: Insight to Action, Fact Sheet and Contextual Navigation: Search and Explore"
    },
    {
        "front": "Elements if User Experience Design",
        "back": "Visual Design, Information architecture, Interaction Design, Usability, Accessibility, Human-computer interaction"
    },
    {
        "front": "Design element that restricts content to certain width via blank space",
        "back": "Letter Boxing"
    },
    {
        "front": "Letter boxing became optional feature, To account for increased average screen sizes letterboxing has been increased to ____ px",
        "back": "1280"
    },
    {
        "front": "In compact mode the default control area of ___ is reduced to ___",
        "back": "3 rem, 2 rem"
    },
    {
        "front": "What different app types can be found in SAP Fiori?",
        "back": "Conceptual, Technical"
    },
    {
        "front": "What technical application types are defined for SAP HANA?",
        "back": "Transactional, Fact Sheets, Analytical"
    },
    {
        "front": "The SAP BAS is based on the ____ open source IDE, Which embarces Microsoft Visual Studio Code Experience.",
        "back": "Eclipse Theia "
    },
    {
        "front": "Which of the following statements are correct with respect to the SAP Business Application Studio?",
        "options": {"A": "BAS is a development environment for SAP ABAP", "B": "BAS is a browser based development environment", "C": "BAS provides application templates as a foundation of highly efficient app development", "D": "BAS is based on an opensource IDE", "E": "BAS provides WYSIWYG tooling"},
        "back": ["B","C","D","E"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What is true of the SAP Business Technology Platform SAP Business Application Studio?",
        "options": {"A": "It requires 0 installation", "B": "Provides only SAP Cloud Programming Capabilities", "C": "It is updated on a regular basis.", "D": "Does only provide one workspace for project organization"},
        "back": ["A", "C"]
    },
    {
        "front": "What are the tasks of the controller in the MVC implementation?",
        "back": "Modfies the model, Modifies the view via API"
    },
    {
        "front": "For rapid OData service development, we provide ___ and ____ programing models on top of CDS Views",
        "back": "RAP, CAP"
    },
    {
        "front": "The Component.js consist of two parts",
        "back": "The new metadata section that defines a reference to the app descriptor, and the preveiously introduced init function that is called when the component is initialized."
    },
    {
        "front": "the ____ of the component is automatically invoked by SAPUI5 when the component is instantiated.",
        "back": "init function"
    },
    {
        "front": "Component inherits from the base class ____ and it is obligatory to call the init function of the base class, in the init function we instantiate our ____ and ____ like we did before in the app controller",
        "back": "sap.ui.core.UIComponent, data model and i18n model"
    },
    {
        "front": "______ function: you can optionally override the initialization of the root view",
        "back": "createContent"
    },
    {
        "front": "sap.m.Page controls can be used as ____ and the aggregation is called ____",
        "back": "pages,pages"
    },
    {
        "front": "SAPUI5 Routing uses a ____ based navigation",
        "back": "hash"
    },
    {
        "front": "The navigation API provides the following functionality:",
        "back": "- Directly triggers navigation to a navigation target with parameters\n- Registers navigation routes and listeners for fragment changes to restore a specific state."
    },
    {
        "front": "SAPUI5 navigation features:",
        "back": "● sap.m.routing.Router - SAPUI5 router class to load the pages and update the URL, (change and replace hash)\n● Routing configuration in the app descriptor\n● Navigation events\n● Animation between pages, (show, slide, fade, flip)"
    }
]
